[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
大卫·马兰：好的 这是CS50 介绍
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50, Introduction
用Python编程
to Programming with Python.
我叫大卫·马兰 这是我们的图书馆周
My name is David Malan, and this is our week on library.
所以库通常是其他人
So libraries are generally files of code that other people
你可以在你自己的程序或库的代码中使用
have written that you can use in your own programs or a library's code
你可以在你自己的程序中使用
that you've written that you can use in your own program,
但也许不仅仅是这个项目 还有其他的项目
but maybe not just this program, but another and another as well.
Python支持这个想法
So Python supports exactly this idea.
这种与他人共享代码的能力 在您自己的项目中共享代码
This ability to share code with others, share code across your own projects.
它是通过所谓的模块来实现的
And it does so by way of what it calls module.
Python中的模块只是一个库
A module in Python is just a library that
通常具有内置于其中的一个或多个功能或其它特征
typically has one or more functions or other features built into it.
通常 库或模块的用途
Generally, the purpose of a library or a module
特别是鼓励代码的可重用性
specifically is to encourage reusability of code
如果你发现自己一次又一次地使用相同类型的函数
if you find yourself using the same types of functions again and again,
相同的功能
the same functionality.
如果您发现自己从旧项目复制和粘贴
If you find yourself copying and pasting from an old project
在你的新项目中 很有可能有机会
into your new project, odds are there's an opportunity there to factor out
你不断复制和粘贴的代码 你不断重复使用
that code that you keep copying and pasting that you keep reusing and put
你可以将它加载到你的程序中
it into a library that you can then load into your programs moving forward
这样我们就不需要复制粘贴
so as to not just copy and paste it and have
到处都是不同的副本
all these different copies all over.
那么Python自带的模块或库有哪些呢？
So what are some of the modules or libraries that Python comes with?
Python自带一个随机库
Well, Python comes with a random library literally,
也就是说 当你安装Python
which is to say that when you install the Python
您的Mac或PC或其他地方的翻译器
interpreter on your Mac or PC or somewhere
在云中 你不仅可以得到Python
in the cloud, not only do you get Python,
你也会得到一大堆模块
you get a whole bunch of modules as well.
这些模块为您提供了
Now, these modules provide you with functions
你不能像打印和输入一样默认访问它们
that you don't have access to just by default like you do print and input.
打印和输入以及其他类似的功能在Python中都可以工作
Print and input and other such functions just work in Python.
但有时功能隐藏在这些模块中
But sometimes functions are tucked away in these modules,
所以你必须更仔细地装载它们
so you have to be more deliberate about loading them
存入计算机的内存
into the computer's memory.
所以 在电脑硬盘上的某个地方 一旦你安装了Python
So somewhere on the computer's hard drive, once you've installed Python,
还有一个文件 很可能是随机文件.py
there is also, it turns out a file, probably called random.py
可能是别人很久以前写的 但你有权访问
that someone else wrote probably long ago but that you have access to.
在随机的.py文件中 可能有一个或多个函数
And in that random.py file, there's probably one or more functions
你自己可以用来做随机的事情
that you yourself can use in order to do things randomly.
这就是说 你怎么能在一个用Python编写的程序中抛硬币呢？
That is to say how could you flip a coin in a program in Python?
在Python语言中 如何选择1到10之间的随机数？
How could you pick a random number between 1 and 10 in Python?
嗯 你需要一点随机性
Well, you need a bit of randomness.
虽然你可以从数学上算出
And while you could figure out mathematically
如何自己编写这样的函数
how to write functions like that yourself,
站在别人的肩膀上要容易得多
it's a lot easier to stand on the shoulders of others who've already
为你解决了那个问题 这样你就可以专注于这个问题了
solved that problem for you so you can focus on the problem
你自己想要解决的问题
that you yourself want to solve.
因此 有关几乎所有Python模块的文档
So for documentation on most any Python module,
你可以去看官方的Python文档
you go to the official Python docs.
您可以转到这样的URL 其中包含该特定模块的文档
And you go to a URL like this where the documentation for that specific module
活着
lives.
在文档中 您将看到一个列表
And within the documentation, you'll see a list
某些模块提供的功能或其他功能
of the functions or other functionality that some module provide.
但是 如何将模块加载到您自己的程序中呢
But how do you go about loading a module into your own program
以便您可以使用该模块中的函数？
so that you can use the functions in that module?
那么 我们需要在Python中使用一个新的关键字 即它的导入
Well, we need a new keyword in Python and namely it's import.
使用Python中的IMPORT关键字可以导入函数的内容
The import keyword in Python allows you to import the contents of the functions
来自Python语言中的某个模块
from some module in Python.
那么 我该如何在实践中使用它呢？
Well, how might I go about using this in practice?
好吧 让我假设在随机模块中存在
Well, let me propose that there exists in that random module
在其他功能中 这一功能
this function among others.
所以我从文档中复制并粘贴了
So I have copied and pasted from the documentation
这是一个名为Choice的函数的摘要
this summary of a function called Choice.
现在 这个函数存在于随机模块中 可以这么说
Now, the function exists in the random module, so to speak,
不是随机模块 是随机模块
not a random module, the random module.
因此 一般来说 文档完全是这样描述的
And so generally the documentation describes it fully like this.
随机选择是您从技术上调用此函数的方式
random.choice is how you would technically call this function,
我们会看到其他的替代方案
though, we'll see alternatives to that.
在括号中 有一个名为S-E-Q的参数表示序列
In parentheses, there is a parameter called S-E-Q for sequence.
序列一般是指一个列表之类的东西
And sequence generally means a list or something
如果你有一个数字或字符串或其他任何东西的列表 它就像列表一样
that is list-like if you have a list of numbers or strings or anything else.
以及详细的文件
And the documentation elaborate.
那么 我该如何使用这个函数来解决 也许
Well, how can I go about using this function to solve, perhaps,
一个熟悉的问题？
a familiar problem?
好吧 让我在这里打开VS Code
Well, let me go ahead and open up VS Code here.
让我建议我们实现一个程序来模拟抛硬币
And let me propose that we implement a program that simulates flipping a coin.
在美国 硬币有正面或反面
A coin that in the US has heads or tails, the idea of which
是选择一个概率为50/50的决策
is to pick a decision with 50/50 probability.
正面和反面各占一半
50% probability of heads, 50% probability of tails.
或者你可以使用其他类似的机制
Or you can use some other mechanism like that.
好的 让我打开一个代码为generate.py的程序
Well, let me go ahead and open a program with code called generate.py
因为我想开始生成一大堆随机信息
because I want to start generating a whole bunch of random information.
第一个就是抛硬币
The first of which is just going to be a coin toss.
那么 如何使用该功能呢？
Now, how do I go about using that function?
首先 我必须导入随机库
Well, I first have to import the random library.
所以我的文件的第一行
So literally the first or among the first lines of my file
应该是随机导入
should be import random.
这样我就可以访问这个特定模块中的所有功能
And that just gives me access to all of the functions in that specific module.
现在 假设我想抛硬币
Now, suppose I want to flip a coin.
嗯 我可以根据刚才的文档做随机选择
Well, I can do random.choice per the documentation a moment ago.
这也需要一个序列
And that again takes a sequence.
什么是序列？
What's a sequence?
这是一个列表或类似列表的东西
It's a list or something that's list-like.
我们知道名单
And we know about lists.
我们用列表来排列数字
We've used lists to iterate over numbers.
我们用名单来筛选霍格沃茨的学生
We've used lists to iterate over students at Hogwarts.
让我们继续讨论一个硬币的两面
Let's go ahead now and iterate over just a list of two sides of a coin,
“正面” 引号 引号 或反面
"heads," quote, unquote, or tails.
现在 我可以把这些东西叫做任何我想要的东西
Now, I could call these anything I want.
这是我的绳子
These are my string.
我只想模拟抛硬币
I just want to simulate a tossing a coin.
所以我只想说正面和反面
So I'm just going to say in all lowercase, heads and tail.
但请注意语法
But notice the syntax.
我把“正面”和“反面”用双引号引起来了
I have "heads" and "tails" in double quotes.
那是因为它们是弦
That's because they're strings.
我也可以使用单引号 只要我始终如一
I could also use single quotes so long as I'm consistent.
它们之间有一个逗号 这意味着列表有两个元素
There's a comma between them, which means the list has two elements.
它们是左边和右边的方括号
They're square brackets to the right and the left, which
表示这确实是一个列表
indicates that this is indeed a list.
这是在Python中定义列表的语法回想
That's the syntax recall for defining a list in Python.
最后 还有一些更熟悉的东西
And then lastly, there's something more familiar.
这些方括号外面有圆括号
There's the parentheses outside of those square brackets.
但这些只是属于Choice函数的括号
But those are just the parentheses that belong to the Choice function
并指定其参数传入的位置
and specify where its parameter gets passed in.
但同样 与过去的函数不同 我必须指定哪个模块
But again, unlike past function, I have to specify what module
这一功能至少目前是可行的
this function is in at least for now.
所以我随机选择来调用特定的函数
And so I do random.choice to call the specific function.
好吧 好吧 在这两者之间抛硬币是一回事
All right, well, it's one thing to flip a coin picking between those
概率为50%
with 50% probability.
这就是随机选择的作用
And that's what random.choice does.
它接受一个列表 并随机返回到其中一个值
It takes in a list, and it returns to one of those values randomly
概率相等
with equal probability.
因为我通过了两个项目 所以我有50%的机会
Because I've passed in two items, I've got a 50/50 chance.
如果我通过了三个项目 那么每一个项目都有33%的可能性
If I passed in three items, it'd be a 33% chance for each of those items
以此类推
and so forth.
Python为您做了计算
Python does the math for you.
但是我想把它的值存储在一个变量中
But I want to store the value of this in a variable.
所以让我们定义一个变量 称为Coin Equals 不管返回值是什么
So let's define a variable called coin equals whatever the return value is.
因此 这确实就像抛硬币一样
So this is indeed like flipping a coin.
我将存储在一个名为Coin的变量中 不管是什么
I'm going to store in a variable called coin, whatever
这个值是 正面或反面
that value is, heads or tails.
现在 为了让我知道发生了什么 让我们继续
And now, just so I can see what's going on, let's go ahead
并打印出那枚字符串硬币的价值
and print out the value of that string coin
好了 现在让我继续在我的终端窗口中运行这个程序
All right, let me go ahead now and run this program in my terminal window.
PythonofGenerate.py 回车
Python of generate.py, Enter.
而且看起来第一个掷硬币的是人头
And it looks like the first coin toss was the heads.
让我们继续 再运行一次
Let's go ahead and run it again.
而且看起来又是正面的
And it looks like it was heads again.
也许你想在这里加入我们的聊天
Maybe you want to chime into the chat here.
如果我第三次运行它 这一次会是什么？
If I run it a third time, what's it going to be this time?
如果你想在聊天中输入你的想法
If you want to type your thoughts in the chat,
您可能会认为这里面有漏洞
you might think there's a bug here.
但这是行动中的可能性
But this is probability in action.
如果我继续第三次按回车键
If I go ahead and hit Enter a third time there,
实际上现在是反面 反面
it's actually now tails And again, tails and again tails and again tails
一次又一次反面 又一次正面
and again tails and again heads.
现在 如果我们这样做无数次
Now, if we did this an infinite number of times,
这确实会是50/50的结果
it would indeed work out to be 50/50.
如果我们只做几次 结果可能不会那么干净利落
If we only do it a few times, it might not work out as cleanly.
但这就是概率的工作原理
But that's how probabilities indeed work.
好了 我现在把它弄好了
All right, so I've got that now working.
我可以用一种不同的方式来实现这一点吗？
Could I have implemented this in a different way?
那么 让我向您展示一种单独使用IMPORT关键字的替代方法
Well, let me show you an alternative to actually using the import keyword alone
让我来介绍一下在Python中的关键字from
and let me introduce the keyword from in Python.
因此 From是可在导入函数时使用的Python中的关键字
So from is a keyword in Python that you can use when importing functions
来自一个模块 但它允许您比单独导入更具体一些
from a module, but it allows you to be a little more specific than import alone.
因此 如果我回到我的代码 它是值得的
So if I go back to my code here, it's worth
注意到从技术上讲 我在这里通过导入随机
noting that what technically I'm doing here by importing random
从技术上讲 我是在导入那个模块中的所有东西
is I'm technically importing everything that's in that module.
因此 不只是这个名为随机选择的函数 还有其他几个函数
So not just the function called random.choice but a few other functions
也是
as well.
因此 与其在我的文件顶部使用这行代码
So instead of using this line of code at the top of my file,
导入随机 从技术上讲 这将允许我访问
import random, which will technically give me access
对于他们所在的所有内容 一个不利的方面是
to all of the contents they're in, a downside of that
我必须输入随机的 选择 随机的 这个
is that I have to type in random.choice, random.this,
随机性 因为我调用的所有函数
random.that because all of the functions I'm calling
必须与该模块的范围相关联
have to be associated with the scope of that module.
好的 假设我只想调用函数作为它的名称 CHOICE
Well, suppose that I just want to call the function as its name, choice.
我也可以这么做
I can do that as well.
让我将这里的第一行替换为来自随机导入选择
Let me replace this first line here with from random import choice.
这样做的有效作用是加载函数的名称选择
And what this does effectively is it loads the function's name choice
放到我当前命名空间中 放到我正在处理的文件的作用域中
into my current namespace into the scope of the file I'm working in.
这意味着我现在不再需要具体说明
What that means is that I now no longer have to specify
我指的是哪种选择功能
which choice function I mean.
我只能说选择
I can just say choice.
因此 它将其加载到本地命名空间中
And so it loads it into the local namespace
这是我的本地词汇 如果你愿意的话 所以我现在可以说选择
that is into my local vocabulary, if you will, so I can just now say choice.
你认为这在什么情况下可能是有利的？
This might be advantageous in what cases, do you think?
您可能希望在什么时候像这样显式导入函数的名称
When might you want to import the name of the function explicitly like this
而不是说是随机的 选择--
as opposed to just saying random.choice--
在调用函数时在代码中进行随机选择吗？
random.choice throughout your code when calling a function?
对于使用from的替代导入 这里有什么直觉吗？
Any instincts here for this alternative import using from?
观众：大家好 我是来自埃及的穆罕默德·奥马尔
AUDIENCE: Hello, I'm Mohammed Omar from Egypt.
也许如果我们有一个变量 它的名字基本上就像Choose
And maybe if we have a variable that its name is basically like choice
如果我有一个叫做选择的变量
if I have a variable called the choice.
因此 我需要区分我选择的托盘
So I need to differentiate which trays I choose.
所以我会选择随机数据选择
So I'm going to choose random data choice.
大卫·马兰：是的 非常好的直觉
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good instincts.
通过使用仅导入随机的第一种方法
By using the first approach by just importing random,
你要确保它的所有内容
you're making sure that all of its contents
与随机模块相关联或被限定为随机模块的范围
are associated with or scoped to the random module
这样你就可以有自己的选择功能了
so that you can have your own choice function.
您可以有自己的选择变量
You can have your own choice variable.
您可以使用与所有函数或变量相同的名称
You can use the same names as all of the functions or variables that
都存储在该文件中 而不会发生冲突
are stored inside of that file without them colliding, so to speak.
这是一件好事
And this is a good thing.
在更老的语言中 情况是这样的 如果你导入某人的库
In older languages, it was the case that if you imported someone's library,
您最好希望您使用的不是相同的函数
you better hope that you're not using the same functions
或变量本身 因为您可能
or variables as they are because you might
实际上存在着某种冲突
in fact have some kind of conflict.
Python和某些其他语言允许您
Python and certain other languages allow you
将这些函数和变量的名称限定为文件或模块
to scope the names of those functions and variables to the file or the module
他们来自哪里
that they come from.
所以这是一件好事
So that's a good thing.
但老实说 这是一个如此短的程序
But honestly, this is such a short program.
或者等同地 也许我使用的是选择函数
Or equivalently, maybe I'm using the choice function
在如此多的地方 人们都叫随机 选择 随机 选择
in so many places calling random.choice, random.choice, random.choice.
这只会让我的代码越来越长
It's just making my code longer and longer and longer.
有点像 但嘿 只是变得又丑又烦
Marginally so, but hey, just getting ugly and annoying,
我可以简单地导入选项 现在稍微收紧我的代码
I can simply import choice and now tighten up my code a little bit.
因此 就像过去的许多决定一样
So as with so many decisions in the past,
不一定只有一种正确的方法
there's not necessarily one right approach or another.
看情况
It depends.
但我认为正是因为这些原因有时候
But I think for those very reasons, sometimes
最好还是像我们第一次那样
it's better to do what we did the first time, which
只是导入模块以保留其中的作用域
is only import the module so as to retain the scope therein.
好吧 让我建议我们过渡到另一个功能
Well, let me propose that we transition to another function that
Python的random模块
comes with Python's random module.
这是从档案里找到的
And that's this here from the documentation randint.
这有点难说 但它意味着返回一个随机整数
It's a bit hard to say, but it implies get back a random int.
如果你读了文档 它是一个介于A和B之间的随机整数
And if you read the documentation, it's a random int that's between A and B
内d
inclusive.
所以如果你把A的1分和B的10分都算进去
So if you were to pass in 1 for A and 10 for B,
你会得到一个介于1和10之间的数字 包括1
you would get back a number between 1 and 10 inclusive, including the 1
并包括潜在的10个
and including the 10 potentially.
每一个都有10%的可能性
Each with a 10% probability.
那么我该如何使用这样的程序呢？
So how might I go about using a program like this?
好 让我回到生成py文件的过程
Well, let me come back to my generate the py file.
为什么我们不继续尝试
And why don't we go ahead and try generating
1到10之间的随机数
a random number between 1 and 10?
在现实世界中 你可能经常这样做
You might do this frequently in the real world.
当你只是想让某人随便选一个数字
When you just want someone to pick a random number,
你在人类的反应中也会告诉他们同样的信息
you tell them as much in the human response.
让我们让电脑在这里做同样的事情
Let's get the computer to do the same here.
让我继续删除我在底部的两行代码
Let me go ahead and delete my two lines of code at the bottom
但我的导入要随机
but keep my import random.
接下来我们定义一个变量 叫做number
And let's go ahead and define a variable this time called number,
将其设置为random.randint的返回值
set it equal to the return value of random.randint
现在传递A 值为1 B 值为10
and now passing A, a value of 1 and B, a value of 10.
现在 让我们继续打印号码
And now, let's go ahead and print the number.
我会在终端窗口
I'm going to go ahead in my terminal window
运行generate.py的Python并按Enter键
and run Python of generate.py and hit Enter.
4.
一个generate.py的Python 然后按Enter
A Python of generate.py and hit Enter.
8 再来 9 再来 7 再来 10 再来 2 再来
8, again, 9, again, 7, again, 10, again, 2, again.
我们可以一整天都这样
And we can do this all day long.
如果我们把所有这些加起来
And if we add all of those up, they should end up
都有10%的概率
being with 10% probability each.
那么 你会如何使用这些信息呢？
Now, how might you use this information?
好吧 也许我们在玩猜谜游戏
Well, maybe we're playing a guessing game.
或者 也许我们正试图将游戏中某个角色的行为随机化
Or maybe we're trying to randomize the behavior of some character in the game.
您可以想象使用像这样非常简单的构建块
You can imagine using very simple building blocks like this just
通过让程序做一些事情来增加程序的趣味性
spicing up your program by getting it to do things
更难预测 因为您似乎选择了这些值
a little less predictably because you're choosing these values seemingly
随机的
randomly.
而你要推迟到Python来做实际的事情
And you're deferring to Python to actually do
这些数字的产生使用它自己的算法和它自己的数学
the generation of these numbers using its own algorithms and its own math.
那么 我们在这里还能做些什么？
Well, what more could we do here?
让我建议我们引入另一个函数
Let me propose that we introduce another function that
来自这个随机图书馆
comes from this random library.
然而 另一个你自己不需要实现的东西 就是洗牌
Yet, another that you yourself don't have to implement, shuffle.
如果您阅读了同一随机模块中的Shuffle文档
If you read the documentation for shuffle in the same random module,
例如 您将看到它包含一个值列表
you'll see that it takes in a list, for instance, of values
然后就把它们洗掉
and just shuffles them up.
它就像一副扑克牌一样让他们随机化
It randomize them like a deck of cards.
在这里 你可能会把它们打乱 让它们看起来像是随机排列的顺序
Here, you might shuffle them so as to put them into seemingly random order.
那么 根据这个函数的名称 我如何使用它呢？
Well, how do I use this based on this function's name?
好吧 让我建议我们回到这里的VS代码
Well, let me propose that we go back to VS Code here.
让我继续下去 这一次做以下事情
And let me go ahead and this time do the following.
因为我需要洗牌之类的东西
Because I need to shuffle something like a deck of cards,
让我继续下去 而不仅仅是随机导入
let me go ahead and not just import random.
但让我给自己一个名为Cards的变量 它的类型是List
But let me give myself a variable called cards that's going to be of type list.
为了让我有东西要洗牌 我
And just so I have something to shuffle, I
不需要在典型的一副牌中包含所有52张牌
don't need all 52 cards in a typical deck.
我要洗三张牌
I'm just going to shuffle three cards.
一个杰克 一个王后和一个国王
A Jack, a Queen, and a King.
我可以随心所欲地叫这些琴弦
I could call those strings anything I want,
但我只是想要一些值的列表 以便将它们打乱
but I just wanted a list of some values so as to shuffle them up.
这就是将其中的顺序随机化
That is randomize the order therein.
那么 现在这是怎么运作的呢？
Well, how does this now work?
如果您阅读随机洗牌的文档
If you read the documentation for random.shuffle,
你会看到它把论据打乱了
you'll see that it shuffles the argument in place.
这与我们看到的许多功能不同
That is unlike many of the functions we have seen.
它不会返回包含以下内容的值
It doesn't return to you a value that contains
在这种情况下洗过的牌
the shuffled cards in this case.
实际上 它会对自己给出的清单进行洗牌
It actually shuffles the list it's given itself.
所以这对我的代码意味着我需要
So what this means for my code is that I need
做这样的事情--随机的.洗牌
to do something like this-- random.shuffle
并传入包含这些卡片的变量
and pass in the variable containing those cards.
然后在这里的最后一行 我应该如何开始打印卡片？
And then on a final line here, how might I go about printing the cards?
嗯 我可以这么做 我可以说打印卡片
Well, I could do this, and I could say print card.
但如果我这样做了 我实际上会看到列表的Python语法
But if I do that, I'm actually going to see Python syntax for lists.
它只是以自己的方式 使用逗号和类似的东西来格式化
And it's just going to format in its own way using commas and the like.
我想把这些卡片一次打印出来一张
I want to print these cards out one at a time
只是因为我认为它看起来会更好一点 这样我们就可以使用我们的一些语法
just because I think it'll look a little better so we can use some of our syntax
从循环中说出这样的话--
from loops and say something like this--
对于卡片中的卡片 请继续打印当前卡片
for card in cards, go ahead and print out the current card.
那么 这里现在发生了什么？
So what's now happening here?
第三行 我按照这个顺序定义了三张牌的列表--
Line three, I'm defining a list of three cards in this order--
杰克 王后 国王
Jack, Queen, King.
然后我在4号线上洗同样的牌
I'm then shuffling those same cards on line four.
然后在第五行 我使用了一个for循环
And then on line five, I'm using a for loop
对于该列表中的每张卡片 一次打印出一张
for each of the cards in that list printed out one at a time
而且因为我一次打印一行
and because I'm using print one line at a time.
好了 让我们来看看结果
Well, let's see the results.
在我的终端窗口里 我要去
Down here in my terminal window, I'm going
运行genate.py的Python并按Enter键
to run Python of generate.py and hit Enter.
王后 国王 杰克似乎拖着脚步 因为那不是
Queen, King, Jack seemingly shuffled because that's not
我之前定义的顺序
the order I defined earlier.
我们再来一次吧
Let's do it again.
皇后 金 杰克
Queen, King, Jack.
嗯 好吧 那正好是一样的
Hmm, OK, that happens to be the same.
但让我们来看看
But let's see.
这可能只是个坏机会
This could just be bad chance.
我们走吧
There we go.
杰克 王后 国王
Jack, Queen, King.
看起来不像是洗牌的 但至少
Doesn't look like it's shuffled, but at least
我们现在得到了不同的订单
we're getting back different orderings now.
再说一次 杰克 王后 国王
Again, Jack, Queen, King.
嗯 不太好
Hmm, not so good.
杰克 王后 国王
Jack, Queen, King.
不怎么好
Not so good.
这是一个你可能想和他打牌的人
This is someone you probably want to play against with cards.
皇后 杰克 金 我们走吧
Queen, Jack, King, there we go.
当然 我们这里只有三张卡
But of course, we only have three cards here.
所以我们可能不会看到那么多的排列
So there's not that many permutations we might see.
如果我们随着时间的推移这样做 我们会看到他们所有的人
And if we do this over time, we will see all of them.
当然 如果我们有13或52张卡片
But if we had, of course, 13 or 52 cards,
相反 我们会看到更多的排列
we'd see a lot more permutations instead.
所以我们现在有三种方法来产生随机信息
So we have now these three ways to generate random information.
第一 如果你想开始某种运动项目 就简单地掷硬币
One, a simple coin toss if you want to start some kind of athletic event.
第一 在1到10之间选一个数字
One, pick a number between 1 and 10 if you
想以此为基础做决定
want to decide something based on that.
现在 使用shuffle 我们甚至可以接收一个列表
And now, using shuffle, we can even take in a list of things
然后把它们打乱 这样我们就得到了某种随机的行为
and shuffle them about so that we get some kind of random behavior.
好吧 让我在这里暂停一下 看看是否有
Well, let me pause here and see if where there's
关于随机数、模块或这三个函数中的任何一个的任何问题
any questions yet on random, on modules, or any of these three functions.
观众：是的 我们可以增加或减少
AUDIENCE: Yeah, can we increase or decrease
如果我们想的话 我们可以计算出卡片的概率
the probability of cards if we want to?
例如 有三个
For example, there are three.
有33%的可能性是B 那么有没有
There is a 33% chance of probable B. So is there
有没有可能增加或减少概率
any chance to increase or decrease the probability?
大卫·马兰：你能把这些概率
DAVID MALAN: Can you set these probabilities
不使用相同的功能？
not using these same functions?
你能设定概率吗？
Can you set the probabilities?
但是你完全可以实现一些你自己的功能
But you can absolutely implement some of your own functions
或者使用这个库和其他库中存在的更复杂的函数
or use more sophisticated functions that do exist in this library and others
来行使更多的控制权
to exercise more control.
这些都是非常用户友好和简单的功能 当然
These are meant to be very user-friendly and simple functions, certainly
我们所看到的 所有这些的概率都是相等的
the ones we looked at, that give you equal probability for all of those.
但你绝对可以歪曲事实 尽管如此 希望
But absolutely you could skew things, though, hopefully,
如果你正在实现一个赌博游戏或类似的游戏
if you're implementing a gambling game or the like,
你并不是真的让某些牌比其他牌更有可能
you're not actually making some cards more probable than others.
现在让我回到我们在这里实现的随机性
Allow me to turn back now to our implementation here of this randomness
并考虑如何利用其他类型的功能
and consider how we might leverage other types of functionality that
并不一定在这个图书馆里
aren't necessarily in this specific library here.
好吧 事实证明 Python还附带了一个统计库
Well, it turns out that Python also comes with a statistics library.
它包含了各种各样的功能
And this contains all sorts of functions for doing
更具有统计性质的东西 即计算
things more statistical in nature, namely calculating
数据集的均值、中位数、众数或其他方面
means or medians or modes or other aspects of a data set
你可能想分析一下
that you might want to analyze.
那么我们如何使用Python中的统计模块呢？
So how might we use the statistics module in Python?
好吧 我们可以先看看它的文档
Well, we might first just take a look at it's documentation
就像Python中的其他模块一样
like any other module in Python.
我们会看到在这个库中有一大堆函数
And we'll see within that library that there's a whole bunch of function.
其中一个功能非常简单
And one of those functions is one that's quite simple.
很一般
It's average.
一个函数 允许您计算一些数字的平均值
A function that allows you to calculate the average of some numbers
你已经通过了
that you've passed in.
让我在终端窗口的VS Code中打开一个新文件
Let me go ahead and in VS Code in my terminal window, open up a new file
名为average.py
called average.py.
在这个文件的顶部 我将导入
And at the top of this file, I'm going to import
这一次是一个不同的库 即Python中的统计模块
a different library this time, namely the statistics module in Python.
现在 我将继续调用一个函数
And now, I'm going to go ahead and call a function that I know comes
在该模块中 即用于某些值平均值
in that module, namely mean for the average of some values.
我要打电话给南极洲
And I'm going to call statistics.mean.
我将传入这个函数mean 一个值的列表
And I'm going to pass into this function mean, a list of some values.
假设我很快地
And let's suppose that I'm quickly trying
来计算我目前在学校的平均成绩
to calculate what my current grade average is in school.
我第一次考试考得很好
And I did really well on my first test.
我得到了100%
And I got 100%.
在我的第二次 我做得很好 但不是那么好
And on my second, I did well but not as well.
我得了90分
And I got a 90.
讽刺的是我数学不好
And ironically, I'm not very good with math.
所以我想知道这两次测试的平均值是多少
So I'd like to figure out what my average now is between those two tests.
现在让我在这个列表中输入
So let me go ahead now and in this list, type in the number
100 逗号 90 从而传入两个值的列表 两个INT 190
100, comma, 90, thereby passing in a list of two values, two INTs, 190.
在这些之外的是圆括号 因为 当然
And outside of those are the parentheses because, of course,
这就是我传递给mean函数的参数
this is now the argument I'm passing to the function called mean.
这个函数mean在statistics模块中
And this function mean is in the module called statistics.
如果我不计算平均值
Well, it's not that interesting to just calculate the mean if I don't actually
看看是什么
see what it is.
让我另外传递均值函数的返回值
So let me additionally pass the return value of that mean function
打印功能像往常一样
to the print function as usual.
现在让我在VS Code的终端窗口中输入
Let me now in my terminal window in VS Code, type
在average.py的Python中 然后按Enter键
in Python of average.py and hit Enter.
瞧 正如你所料 我的平均分是95%
And voila, as you might expect, my average is 95%.
所以这里的不同之处在于我只是使用了一个不同的模块
So the difference here is that I'm just using a different module that
仍然与Python一起提供
still comes with Python.
但我需要导入它 而不是导入随机模块
But I need to import it instead of, for instance, the random module instead.
这一次 我从文件中得知
And this time, I know from the documentation
存在一个叫做Mean的函数
that there exists a function called mean.
事实证明 在Python中还附带了更多的功能
Well, it turns out there's even more functionality that comes with Python
这是随其他Python模块一起提供的
and that comes with other modules in Python.
这个特性通常被称为命令行参数
And there's this feature generally known as command line arguments.
这不仅是Python的一个特性 也是语言的一个特性
This is a feature, not just of Python, but of languages
更广泛地说 这允许您提供输入 而不是何时
more generally that allow you to provide input not when
在程序内部提示 就像我们每次调用Python函数时发生的那样
prompted inside of a program as happens whenever we call the Python function
输入
input.
相反 有这样一个功能 程序的命令行参数
But rather, there's this feature, command line arguments of programs,
这允许您提供以下参数
that allows you to provide arguments that
是程序的输入 当你在命令行执行的时候
is input to the program of just when you're executing at the command line.
所以到目前为止 例如 回想一下 我们通常
So up until now, for instance, recall that we've generally
运行Something.py的Python
run Python of something.py.
例如 hello.py的Python
For instance, Python of hello.py.
我从来没有真正执行过任何单词或短语
And I've never once really executed any words or phrases
以文件的名字命名 但我可以
after the name of the file, but I could.
事实上 当你像我们一样在类似命令的环境中运行程序时
In fact, when you're running programs in a command-like environment like we are,
您可以在命令后提供任意数量的单词、数字或短语
you can provide any number of words or numbers or phrases after the command
你在打字
that you're typing.
所有这些都会以某种方式作为输入传递到程序本身
And all of those will somehow be passed in as inputs to the program itself.
您不必一次提示用户做一件事
You don't have to prompt the user for one thing at a time
通过手动调用该输入函数
by manually calling that input function.
那么 这实际上意味着什么呢？
So what does this mean in real terms?
好了 让我们回到VS代码这里
Well, let me go ahead back into VS Code here.
让我建议我们考虑如何利用某个模块
And let me propose that we consider how we might leverage a certain module.
我将继续创建一个名为name.py的文件
I'm going to go ahead and create a file called name.py.
这次我想用一个新模块 那就是
And I'd like to use a new module this time that's
这将使我能够访问在命令行中键入的值
going to give me access to values that have been typed at the command line.
但是这个模块会是什么呢？
But what's this module going to be?
好的 这个将被命名为sys
Well, this one's going to be called sys.
sys是system的缩写 它包含了很多功能
And sys, short for system, contains a whole lot of functionality
这是特定于系统本身和你我正在输入的命令
that's specific to the system itself and the commands that you and I are typing.
此模块的文档位于此URL
The documentation for this module is at this URL here.
它列出了所有的函数和变量
And it lists all of the various functions and variables and the like
模块附带的功能
that come with that module.
但我们要关注一些更具体的东西
But we're going to focus on something a little more specific,
也就是这个东西
namely this thing here.
在Python的sys模块中
It turns out in the sys module in Python,
有一个变量 就像魔法一样存在 叫做argv
there is a variable that just magically exists for you called argv.
它代表论点向量 这是一种描述
It stands for argument vector which is a fancy way of describing
人类在提示符下输入的所有单词的列表
the list of all of the words that the human typed in at their prompt
在他们按回车键之前
before they hit Enter.
所有这些似乎都是通过Python神奇地提供给您的
All of those are seemingly magically provided to you via Python
一个名为sys.argv的变量
in a variable called sys.argv.
这个变量是一个列表 这意味着第一个元素将
This variable is a list, which means that the first element is going
你输入的第一个词
to be the first word that you type.
第二个元素是第二个单词
The second element is going to be the second word
你输入的信息等等
that you typed in, so forth.
通过这个列表 你能找出
And by way of this list, then, can you figure out
人类在提示符下实际输入了哪些单词
what words did the human actually type at the prompt and maybe use that
来影响你自己程序的行为
to influence the behavior of your own program?
那么 这意味着什么呢？
So what does this mean now in real terms?
在这个名为name.py的新选项卡中 让我继续导入sys
Well, in this new tab called name.py, let me go ahead and import sys.
在sys模块中 将允许我访问sys.argv 但是如何才能
Within that sys module is going to give me access to sys.argv, but how might
我想用它？
I want to use it?
好吧 我们开始吧
Well, let's do this.
而不是写一个Hello World程序
Instead of writing a Hello World program that all of these times
刚刚查找了输入的返回值
has just looked for the return value of input
来弄清楚用户想让我打印什么
to figure out what the user wants me to print,
让我们继续 只是期待用户告诉我们
let's go ahead and just expect the user to tell us
当他们运行Python程序本身时 他们的名字是什么
when they run the Python program itself, what their name is.
假设这一次 我想生成一大堆名字标签
And suppose this time, I'd like to generate a whole bunch of name tags,
最初只有一个
initially just one.
在美国这里 在翻领上贴一张贴纸是很常见的
And in the US here, it's very common to wear a sticker on your lapel that
你好 我叫大卫
says Hello, my name is David.
所以我想打印出一些类似的文本
So I want to print out some text that resembles that.
我的想法是也许有一天我可以增强这个程序
The idea being maybe I could enhance this program someday
直接把文本发送到打印机
to even send that text straight to the printer
并动态生成这些名称标签
and dynamically generate those name tags.
好吧 让我继续做这个
Well, let me go ahead now and do this.
让我像往常一样打印出来 你好
Let me go ahead and print out as always, Hello.
但这次我要多说点
But I'll say a little something more this time
让事情变得更有趣
to make things more interesting.
你好 我叫“是” 引用 不引用
Hello, my name "is," quote, unquote.
在那之后 我通常
And then after that, I normally have been
在调用input的习惯中 将返回值存储在变量中
in the habit of calling input, storing the return value in a variable,
并在这里传入该变量的名称
and passing in the name of that variable here.
但我还是要直接跳到这个
But I'm going to instead jump right to this--
sys.argvbracket1.
就这样
And that's it.
我会有一个程序说你好 我的名字被跟踪了
I'm going to have a program here that says Hello, my name is followed
sys.argvbracket1中的任何内容
by whatever is in sys.argvbracket1.
注意 这个.argv也是一个列表
And notice, this .argv again is a list.
回顾我们对循环和循环列表的讨论
And recall from our discussion of loops and in turn list,
我们用这个方括号来表示不同的元素
we use this square bracket notation to get at the various elements
在一个列表中
inside of a list.
好吧 让我现在下去到终端窗口
All right, let me go down now into my terminal window
然后运行name.py的Python
and run Python of name.py.
但这一次
But this time, rather than just hit Enter
等待程序提示输入我的名字
and wait for the program to prompt me for my name,
让我主动告诉这个程序我的名字
let me proactively just tell this program what my name is
所谓的命令行
at the so-called command line.
开始吧
Here we go.
D-A-V-I-D与文件名之间用空格分隔 因此
D-A-V-I-D separated with a space from the name of the file so that now when I
执行Python name.py大卫 我在屏幕上看到 瞧 你好
execute Python, name.py David, I see on the screen, voila, Hello,
我叫大卫
my name is David.
所以仅基于这个演示 我认为
So based on this demonstration alone, I think
我们可以准确地推断出sys.argv中发生了什么
we can infer exactly what's going on in sys.argv
尽管乍看起来很复杂
even though it sounds certainly at first glance, rather complicated here.
我们往上看
Let's look up.
在sys.argv中 我在这里将括号1括起来
At sys.argv, I'm going to bracket1 here.
所以很明显 sys.argvbracket1存储的是D-A-V-I-D 但它是一个
So clearly, sys.argvbracket1 is storing D-A-V-I-D. But it's one.
回想一下 在过去我们研究循环时
In the past when we looked at loops, recall
我们说它们是零指数
that we said that they were zero index.
第一个元素是零
That is the first element is zero.
下一个元素是1
The next element is one.
下一个元素是2 依此类推
This next element is two and so forth.
然而 在这里 我把它当作我的名字
And yet, here I am treating it as though my name
位于列表一的开头
is at the start of the list one.
那么 让我问这个问题 在sys.argv的0中可能是什么？
Well, let me ask this question, what is probably in sys.argv of 0?
0的sys.argv中可能有什么--
What is probably in sys.argv of 0--
列表中的第一个元素是什么？
the very first element actually in that list?
观众：哦 是的
AUDIENCE: Oh, yeah.
我想它就像C中的程序名
I think it's like in C, the name of program.
大卫·马兰：的确 这和C语言很像
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, it's indeed like in C. Another language
是程序的名称
is the name of the program.
如果我们考虑一下我打的是什么
Well, if we consider what it was I typed,
我当然输入了Python 因为这是我的解释器的名字
I certainly typed Python because that's the name of my interpreter.
我们真的不需要知道这一点 因为我们使用的是Python本身
And we don't really need to know that because we're using Python itself.
但在那之后 我打了两个字
But after that, I did type two things.
我输入了name.py 就像我在任何时候做过很多次一样
I typed name.py as I've done so many times any time
我想要在我编写的解释器程序中使用Python
I want Python to the interpreter program I've written.
事实证明 按照惯例
And it turns out by convention, what Python
它是否将正在执行的文件的名称存储在sys.argv中
does is it stores in sys.argv the name of the file that you're executing
或口译 后跟您键入的任意数量的其他单词
or interpreting followed by any number of other words that you type.
所以这段时间 我们可能一直在访问
So all this time, we could have been accessing
这个节目的名字 坦率地说 并不是那么有趣
the name of the program, which frankly, isn't all that interesting.
但我们现在也可以访问在提示符后输入的单词
But we can also now access words that are typed after that prompt as well.
当然 如果我不输入任何内容 这里可能会发生什么？
But of course, if I don't type anything in, what might happen here?
我可能太天真了 以为总会有
This might be naive of me to assume that there's always
将会出现在sys.argv中的位置1处
going to be something at location1 in sys.argv.
让我来试试这个
Let me go ahead and try this.
Python.name.py
Python, name.py.
我不会给你我的名字 因为在这一点上
And I'm not giving you my name because at this point,
我甚至可能不知道你想把我的名字打出来
I might not even know that you want my name to be typed.
现在让我按Enter键
So let me hit Enter now.
呃 哦 我们现在看到一个错误
And uh, oh, we see now an error.
这是一个新的异常 这是在Python中的一个所谓的例外
A so-called exception in Python, this one's a new one.
这是一个索引错误 它详细说明了列表索引超出范围
This one's an index error that elaborates list index out of range.
事实证明 这实际上是最常见的错误之一
And turns out this is actually one of the most common mistakes
在编程中 无论您使用的是Python中的列表
in programming, whether you're using a list in Python
或其他语言中的数组或向量 是
or arrays or vectors in other languages, is
尝试访问某些不存在的元素
to try to access some element that does not exist.
你试着向左走得太远
You try to go too far to the left.
或者您尝试在此对象中向右走得太远
Or you try to go too far to the right in this object that
只是一些值的列表
is just a list of some values.
所以当然 这里的错误是我是
So of course, the mistake here is that I'm
假设地点1会有什么东西
assuming there's going to be something at location1
实际上 它是位置0
when really, it's location0.
这是唯一有价值的东西
That's the only one that has a value.
但解决这个问题并不等同于做bracket0
But fixing this is not going to amount to doing bracket0
因为现在如果我继续运行这个程序 没有其他词
because now if I go ahead and rerun this program with no other words
在name.py之后 它会说你好 我的名字是name.py 这很好
after name.py, it says Hello, my name is name.py, which is fine
如果我们要为这个项目做一个名牌 但那不是
if we're making a name tag for the program, but that's not,
当然 我在这里的目标是
of course, what my goal here is instead.
因此 如果解决办法不仅仅是将1改为0
So if the fix is not just to change the one to a zero,
我还能怎么处理这个错误呢？
how else might I handle this error?
How else might I handle this error?
如果用户不记得 就会出现这种索引错误
This index error that happens if the user just doesn't remember to
或者不知道在提示符下输入他们的真实姓名
or doesn't know to type their actual name at the prompt.
观众：我们总是可以在节目中加入一个例外
AUDIENCE: We could always put an exception into the program,
比方说 如果地点1什么都没有 我们就出来
say, if there's nothing at location1, we just come out
然后说 好的 我们没有参数什么的
and say, OK, we haven't got parameter or something.
但如果有的话 我们会继续这个项目
But if there is, we continue along with the program.
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
因此 如果我可以简化一下 我们可以尝试执行这行代码
So if I might simplify, we can try to execute this line of code,
除非出现错误 我们会以其他方式处理
except if there's an error, we'll deal with it in some other way.
现在 理想的情况是 一旦我成为一个足够强大的程序员
Now, ideally-- and once I'm a strong enough programmer,
我已经预料到了这一点 并编写了以下代码
I would have anticipated this and written the following code
从一开始
from the get go.
但当你在学习的时候 看到一个错误当然是合理的
But when you're learning, it's certainly reasonable to see an error.
哦 我没有意识到我应该发现这一点 然后
Oh, I didn't realize I should detect that and then
返回并改进您的代码
go back and improve your code.
但当然 如果你阅读了文档
But of course, if you read the documentation,
你牢牢记住了从过去学到的一些教训
you ingrain some of the lessons learned from the past.
您将养成尝试并检查其中一些异常的习惯
You'll get into the habit of trying and checking for some of these exceptions
你自己
yourself.
所以让我像你在这里提议的那样 用一种可能的方式来解决这个问题
So let me solve this in one possible way as you've proposed here.
让我们尝试按如下方式处理此异常
Let's try to handle this exception as follows.
现在让我继续说下去
Let me go ahead now.
而不是盲目地给这条打印线打电话
And instead of just blindly calling this print line,
让我试着打印出来你好 我的名字是某某
let me try to print out Hello, my name is such and such,
除非出现问题 特别是索引错误 否则
except if there is an issue, specifically an index error, then
我想要做什么呢？
what do I want to go ahead and do?
我要说的是 论点太少了
I'm going to say something like too few arguments.
我可以解释得更清楚
I could be more explanatory than that.
但现在 我只想向用户解释
But for now, I'm just going to explain to the user
他们给我的论据太少 提示时的话太少
that they gave me too few arguments, too few words at the prompt.
所以现在 它仍然不会以我想要的方式工作
So now, it's still not going to work in quite the way I want.
我还是不能生成他们的名牌
I'm still not going to be able to generate their name tag.
但至少 他们不会看到一些隐晦的错误消息
But at least, they're not going to see some cryptic error message
并认为是他们自己破坏了程序
and think that they themselves broke the program.
现在让我继续运行名为e.py、Enter和参数太少的Python
Let me go ahead now and run Python of name.py Enter and too few arguments.
好的 现在让我继续执行名为.py的Python 然后输入我的名字David
OK, let me go ahead now and do Python of name.py and type in my name, David.
现在我们又重回正轨了
And now we're back in business.
我看到我的名字也在屏幕上
And I see that my name is on the screen too.
但严格地说 我不需要尝试这样做
But strictly speaking, I don't have to try to do this.
在编写这段代码时 我实际上可以更具防御性
I could actually be a little more defensive in writing this code.
也许我可以检查用户是否真的
And maybe I could check whether or not the user has indeed
在提示符下提供一个或多个名称 以便提供这些名称
provided a name or multiple names at the prompt so as to give them
更精炼的错误消息也是如此
more refined error messages as well.
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how might I do this?
好了 我去撤销我添加的异常处理
Well, me go and undo the exception handling I've added.
为什么我不更谦虚地尝试这样做呢？
And why don't I instead more modestly try to do this?
让我继续在这里介绍一个有条件的
Let me go ahead and introduce a conditional here.
如果sys.argv的长度小于2或等价于仅等于1
If the length of sys.argv is less than 2 or equivalently equal to just one
价值--
value--
但我现在只会坚持少于2个
but I'll just stick with less than 2 for now,
然后继续打印出两个论点
then go ahead and print out two few arguments.
所以我最终想要两个论点
So I want ultimately two arguments.
我想知道0号位置的程序名称
I want the name of the program at location0.
我要知道地点1的那个人的名字
And I want the name of the human at location1.
这总共有两个论点
So that's a total of two arguments.
所以如果我的论点少于两个 让我们
So if I have fewer than two arguments, let's
用这行打印行告诉用户 L如果sys.argv的长度
tell the user with this print line, L if the length of sys.argv
就是说大于2 就像他们在提示符下输入了太多的单词
is say greater than 2, like they typed in too many words at the prompt, well,
让我们告诉他们 打印 引用 取消引用 太多的论点
let's tell them, print, quote, unquote, "too" many arguments.
如果他们真的做对了 他们给了我两个论点
Else if they did get it right, and they gave me exactly two arguments.
否则 让我们继续打印我真正关心的内容
Else, let's go ahead and print what I actually care about.
好的 让我去我的终端窗口
All right, let me go down to my terminal window
在这里 运行名为e.py的Python 看吧
here and run Python of name.py and voila.
啊 哦 一种完全不同类型的错误
Uh, oh, a completely different type of error.
这是一个语法错误 我们在过去已经看到过
This one a syntax error, which we've seen in the past.
现在 语法错误召回是我的错 就像 我把这里搞砸了
Now, a syntax error recall is mea culpa, like, I messed up here.
我写了无效的语法
And I wrote invalid syntax.
所以没有太多的条件或异常处理
And so no amount of conditionals or exception handling's
真的要赶上这一次了
really going to catch this one.
我需要回去拿回我的程序
I need to go back and just get my program
工作 因为它根本没有运行
to work because it's not running at all.
好的 让我上去看看
Well, let me go up here and see.
第四行是问题所在
Line four is the issue.
事实上 看起来我这里有一根未结束的字符串
And indeed, it looks like I have an unterminated string here.
我需要继续下去 现在添加这个双引号
I need to go ahead and now add this double quote.
所以现在让我继续下去
So let me go ahead now.
转移注意力后 让我重新运行名为e.py的Python 然后按Enter键
And with that red herring gone, let me rerun Python of name.py and hit Enter.
现在 我们看到的论据太少了
And now, we see too few arguments.
好吧 也许它想要我的全名
OK, maybe it wants my full name.
现在让我继续运行名为.py的巨蟒 David Malan
Let me go ahead now and run Python of name.py, David Malan,
在文件名后面输入两个单词 然后按Enter键
typing in both words after the name of the file and hit Enter.
现在 当然 争论太多了
And now, of course, it's too many arguments.
很好
Fine.
现在 我将执行名为e.py且仅名为David的Python
Now, I'll oblige and do Python of name.py and just David.
现在我们就知道了
And there we have it.
屏幕上印着我的名牌
My name tag printed on the screen.
所以严格地说 我们不需要处理异常
So strictly speaking, we don't have to handle exceptions
如果我们能更聪明一点 检查一下
if we can be a little smarter about it and just check for the things
我们所担心的 特别是如果我们想
that we're worried about, especially if we want
为用户提供更精致的建议
to give the user more refined advice.
我们不想就这样告诉他们不 出了点问题
We don't want to just tell them no, something went wrong
否则我们就不想通过
or we don't want to pass.
我们想告诉他们不 要么太少 要么不 太多了
We want to tell them no, that's too few or no, that's too many.
我们的词汇中已经有条件句了
We have conditionals in our vocabulary already
我们现在可以通过它来表达这一点
via which we can now express that.
好吧 让我在这里停一下 看看现在有没有什么问题
Well, let me pause here and see if there's any questions now
关于我们之前如何处理索引错误的错误
on how we handled the error before with the index error
或者现在我们只是主动地完全避免了所有索引错误
or how now we're just proactively avoiding all index errors altogether
先查一下 是不是太少了？
by just checking first, is it too few?
是不是太多了？
Is it too many?
或者这就是我们想要的？
Or is it exactly what we want?
观众：嗨 是的 谢谢
AUDIENCE: Hi, yeah, thank you.
所以我在想 你提到了你的全名
So I was wondering, you touched upon using your full name.
有没有什么办法可以让我们
Is there a way going forwards that perhaps we
有想要他们的全名而只想要他们的名字的人
have people that want their full names and want just their first name
我们把它分成 哦 这个人有全名
that we separate that into, oh, this person has full name.
这个人只有一个名字？
This person has just the one name?
大卫·马兰：当然 请允许我提议我们回来
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely, and allow me to propose we come back
对多个名称的支持
to that support for multiple names.
但事实上 我们可以做到这一点
But indeed, we could do that.
不过 我也应该指出 我们可以支持
And I should note too, though, we can support
如果我这么做的话现在就叫全名
full names right now if I do this.
而不是输入David space Malan 这是有问题的 因为再次
Instead of typing in David space Malan, which is problematic because again,
根据argv是如何工作的定义 每个单词
by definition of how are argv works, each word
最终出现在列表中的特定位置
ends up in a specific location in the list.
但如果我在命令行添加引号、单引号或双引号
But if I add quotes, single quotes or double quotes at the command line,
现在 Python将把这看作是两件事
now, Python will view this as two total things.
文件的名称和此全名
The name of the file and this full name.
现在 当我按Enter键时 我看不到引号
And now, when I hit Enter, I don't see the quotes.
整件事都是作为我的全名传进来的
The whole thing is passed in as my full name.
如果我想让它进一步适应多个人
And if I want to adapt this further for multiple people,
我们也能做到这一点
we'll be able to do that as well.
这个版本上的其他问题现在与If、Elif、Else或On有关 但之前没有
Other questions now on this version with if, elif, else, or on except before.
观众：巨蟒
AUDIENCE: Python.
我想问你 我们可以使用多个其他人的陈述吗？
I want to ask you, can we use multiple else's statement?
大卫·马兰：你能用多个其他人的陈述吗？
DAVID MALAN: Can you use multiple else's statements?
不 Else是你可以拥有的最后一条笼统的声明
No, else is the last catchall statement that you can have.
中间可以有多个elif语句 但不能有多个else
You can have multiple elif statements in the middle but not multiple elses.
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
大卫·马兰：好的
DAVID MALAN: All right.
好了 现在让我们把注意力转回到这个代码上
All right, well, let's turn our attention back now to this code
看看我们能不能通过添加
and see if we can't refine it a bit more by adding
在一些额外的功能中 我们可以使用像sys模块这样的模块
in some additional functionality that we get with modules like the sys module.
我不喜欢这个版本的代码的原因之一是
One of the things I don't love about this version of the code
尽管现在可以说它是正确的 但我的程序的本质
even though arguably it is now correct is that the essence of my program,
它只是打印出姓名标签 被归类到这个Else子句
which is just to print out the name tag, is relegated to this else clause.
这很好
And that's fine.
从逻辑上讲 这是正确的 但总的来说
Logically, it's correct, but generally speaking,
保留你所有的错误是有好处的
there is something nice about keeping all of your error
与您真正需要的代码分开处理
handling separate from the code that you really
关心所有这些if、elif 可能位于代码的顶部
care about having all of these ifs, elifs, perhaps at the top of your code
他们正在检查以确保所有数据都是预期的
that are checking to make sure that all of the data's as expected.
但如果只是为了设计的缘故 那就太好了
But then it would be nice if only for design sake
不要在这个Else语句中隐藏您关心的实际代码
not to hide in this else statement the actual code that you care about.
例如 我更愿意做一些符合逻辑的事情
I would prefer, for instance, to do something logically like this.
我可以在上面检查错误
I could check for errors up top.
然后在这里 打印名牌
And then down here, print the name tag.
如果这些代码是截然不同的代码块 那就太好了
It would be nice if those are distinct blocks of code all of which
在这里左对齐
are here left aligned.
但我刚才所做的事情有个问题
But there's a problem with what I've just done here.
从逻辑上讲 我刚刚通过去掉其他
Logically, what bug did I just introduce by getting rid of the else
并单独引入第10行 没有缩进
and introducing line 10 on its own with no indentation
除了有条件的？
outside of the conditional?
我刚刚引入了什么错误？
What bug have I just introduced?
需要澄清的错误是什么？
What mistake to be clear?
观众：名字有误
AUDIENCE: Name error.
David Malan：具有讽刺意味的是 这是一个名称错误 但不是一个名称错误例外
DAVID MALAN: Ironically, it's a name error but not a name error exception.
我的名字有误 但我想你为我定下了心
It's an error with my name, but I think you're frozen for me.
它将引发一个异常 因为即使
It's going to raise an exception because even
虽然我在上面检查sys.argv的长度
though I'm checking the length of sys.argv up top
即使我再次检查它是否大于2 而不是小于2
and even though I'm checking it again for being greater than 2, not just less
比2 但更大 我仍然盲目和错误地假设
than 2, but greater, I'm still then blindly and incorrectly assuming
它现在将会存在
it's now going to exist.
所以 为了清楚起见 如果我运行名为name.py的Python 并且我没有输入任何参数--
So just to be clear, if I run Python of name.py and I don't type any argument--
我的钱太少了--
I've got too few--
我想我会发现我的钱太少了
I think I'm going to see that I have too few,
但我也会看到同样的例外
but I'm also going to see that same exception.
在我的终端窗口输出的最顶端
At the very top of my terminal window's output,
这是我的错误消息 参数太少了
there's my error message, too few arguments.
但是 在第10行 我盲目地继续索引到我的列表
But again, on line 10, I blindly proceed to still index into my list
在不存在的位置1
at location1 which does not exist.
所以事实证明 有一种更好的方法来处理这样的错误 特别是
So it turns out there's a better way to handle errors like this, especially
如果你用Python写程序
if you're writing a program in Python that's just meant
短暂运行然后退出
to run briefly and then exit anyway.
但如果程序本身
But maybe we could start to exit prematurely if the program itself just
无法继续
can't proceed.
如果用户没有提供我们想要的数据
If the user has not given us the data we want,
也许我们应该提前退出程序
perhaps, we should just exit the program earlier than we might otherwise.
所以让我继续这样做
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续下去 删除我的注释 以便只关注这里的代码
Let me go ahead and remove my comments so as to focus only on the code here.
让我提议 除了印刷
And let me propose that instead of just printing,
引用 取消引用 “太”少的参数 我将使用另一个函数
quote, unquote, "too" few arguments, I'm going to use one other function that
带有sys模块
comes with the sys module.
我将继续并调用sys.exit
I'm going to go ahead and call sys.exit.
正如它的名字所暗示的那样 它会做到这一点
And as the name suggests, it's going to do exactly that.
在系统的帮助下 它会在那里退出我的程序
With the system's help, it's going to exit my program then and there
四号线
on line four.
为什么可以？
Why is that OK?
如果你给我的论据太少
Well, if you gave me too few arguments, I
我对用户没什么好说的了
have nothing more to say to you, the user.
我可能会提前退出
I might as well exit a bit prematurely.
我也可以在6号线上这样做
And I can do this as well on line six.
让我们继续 不只是打印出来 而是系统退出 引用 不引用
Let's go ahead and not just print that, but sys.exit, quote, unquote,
“太多”的争论
"too" many arguments.
打印出这条信息 然后就在那里退出
Print out that message and just exit right there.
我可以相信当我到第八行的时候
Now, I can trust that by the time I get to line eight,
每一个错误条件都已经检查过了
every error condition has been checked for.
所以我可以假设在位置1确实有一个物品
And so it's safe for me to assume that there is in fact an item at location1
在sys.argv中
in sys.argv.
让我继续运行这个 Python
So let me go ahead now and run this, Python
的name.py 输入 参数太少
of name.py, Enter, too few arguments.
但我又回到了我的提示
But I'm back at my prompt.
什么都没发生
Nothing more has happened.
我再检查一遍
Let me run it again.
Python的name.py大卫马兰没有报价 输入
Python of name.py David Malan with no quotes, Enter.
现在这里打印了太多的参数
Too many arguments is now printed here.
最后 名为e.py的Python只需David 回车
Finally, Python of name.py just David, Enter.
你好 我叫大卫
Hello, my name is David.
因此 我们在sys中有两种形式的功能
So we have then in sys two forms of functionality.
现在 我们可以访问这个变量sys.argv 这个自变量向量
Now, we have access to this variable, sys.argv, this argument vector,
这给了我在提示符下输入的所有单词
that gives me all of the words that were typed at the prompt,
包括程序自己的文件名
including the program's own file name.
事实证明 如果我们进一步阅读文档
And it turns out if we read further in the documentation,
有一个出口函数 可以接受不同类型的输入
there's an exit function that can take different types of input.
但如果我传递一个这样的字符串 它确实会为我打印该字符串
But if I pass out a string like this, it will indeed print that string for me
然后当场退出我的程序
and then exit from my program then and there.
现在关于退出这样的节目的问题
Questions now on exiting from programs like this.
需要明确的是 在这段时间里 一旦Python到达文件的底部
To be clear, all of this time once Python gets to the bottom of your file,
它无论如何都会退出的
it's going to exit anyway.
所以我现在使用sys.exit 只是为了确保我早于
So I'm using sys.exit now just to make sure that I exit earlier than
否则的话
otherwise.
观众：我的问题是关于那个系统--
AUDIENCE: My question is about the sys that arg--
阿格夫
argv.
那么 它有能力同时接受或接受多种元素吗？
So is that capable of accepting or taking multiple elements at once?
例如 让我们假设 Pythonname.py David Malan
Let's say, for example, Python name.py, David Malan.
我是一名男性 20岁
I'm a male, 20 years old.
假设我只想访问你的名字 这是第一个索引
And if let's say I only want to access your name, which is at the first index.
然后你的年龄 比方说 在第六位
And then your age is, say, at the sixth index.
我可以输入sys.argv1 然后再输入一个for Six来访问我想要的内容吗？
Can I say sys.argv1 and another one for six to access what I just want?
这都是给sys.argv的吗？
Is that both for sys.argv?
David Malan：简短的回答--是的 我想如果我理解你的问题
DAVID MALAN: Short answer-- yes, I think if I understand your question
正确地说 你是在提议
correctly, whereby, you're proposing to have
在命令的末尾有许多单词
many words at the end of the command.
你想要访问这些单独的单词
And you want to access those individual words.
绝对一点儿没错
Absolutely.
在某种程度上 它会变得有点脆弱 我会说
At some point, it gets a little fragile, I would say,
如果您在提示符下输入的单词太多 那么顺序真的很重要
if you're typing so many words at the prompt that the order really matters.
所以事实证明 有很多项目
And so it turns out there's a lot of programs.
而且 在Python中有一些功能可以
And there's functionality in Python that can
允许您提供这些值 如姓名或年龄
allow you to provide those values, like name or age
或以任意顺序排列的任意数量的其他字段
or any number of other fields in any order
您想要的 但需要以文本形式传入更多信息
you want, but a pass in a bit more information textually
这会告诉程序您想要如何使用它
that tells the program how you want to use it.
所以简而言之 你所描述的一切都是可能的
So in short, what you're describing is possible.
让我做一个小化身 如下所示
And let me do a small incarnation of it as follows.
让我建议我们在这里回到我的代码
Let me propose that we go back to my code here.
让我们假设我们现在实际上想要
And let's propose that we actually now want
在提示符下支持多个值
to support multiple values at the prompt.
所以不会有太多的争论
So there's going to be no such thing as too many arguments.
假设我不仅要为David生成姓名标签 而且还要为David生成姓名标签
Suppose that I want to generate name tags not just for David, but for David,
为了卡特 为了荣申 为了集团中的其他人
for Carter, for Rongshin, for others in the group who
所有人都想要自己的名牌
all want their name tags as well.
所以我要继续做这件事
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要摆脱我的埃利夫病症
I'm going to get rid of my elif condition
因为我不想限制最大字数
because I don't want to limit the maximum number of words
它们不再是在提示符下键入的
that are typed at the prompt anymore.
相反 我想在提示符下遍历每个名字
I instead want to iterate over every name at the prompt.
所以我要说的是
So I'm going to say this.
对于arginsys.argv 继续并打印出来 arg
For arginsys.argv, go ahead and print out this time, arg.
那我在这里做什么？
So what am I doing here?
嗯 尽管语法有一点不同
Well, even though the syntax is a little different,
这个想法和以前我们有循环的时候是一样的
the idea's the same as before when we've had loop.
我正在使用for循环来迭代列表
I'm using a for loop to iterate over a list.
这里有问题的列表是sys.argv
The list in question here is sys.argv.
Arg是我动态创建的变量
Arg is a variable that I'm creating on the fly.
For循环将确保第一次通过此循环时 arg
The for loop is going to make sure that the first time through this loop, arg
设置为命令行上的第一个单词
is set to the first word on the command line.
在第二次循环中 Python的
The second time through the loop, Python's
确保Arg现在设置为命令行上的第二项内容
going to make sure that arg is now set to the second thing on the command line
以此类推
and so forth.
这就是for循环的工作方式
That's just how a for loop works.
它会为我们更新变量
It updates the variable for us.
我不一定要叫它Arg
I don't have to call it arg.
我可以叫它的名字 只要我在两个地方都把它改成名字
I could call it name so long as I change it to name in both places.
但是 如果我迭代更一般的参数 Arg是合理的
But arg is reasonable if I'm iterating over arguments more generally.
不幸的是 如果我现在运行这个程序
If I now run this program, though, unfortunately, there's
有一点小毛病
a little bit of a bug.
即使我输入大卫、卡特和荣申
Even if I type in David and Carter and Rongshin,
我不会只拿到三个名牌的
I'm not going to get just three name tags.
在你的脑海里 有没有人看到我即将被绊倒的虫子？
In your mind, does anyone see the bug I'm about to trip over?
如果我有足够的名牌 这不是一个巨大的交易
It's not a huge deal if I've got enough name tags to go around.
但我会浪费一个因为
But I'm going to be wasting one because this
将打印不是三个 而是四个姓名标签 其中 第一个包含
is going to print not three, but four name tags, whereby, the first contains
程序本身的名称
the name of the program itself.
也许没什么大不了的
Maybe not a big deal.
也许这是我们懒得分发的贴纸 但这是浪费
Maybe that's the sticker we don't bother handing out, but it's wasteful.
看上去确实不对
And it does look wrong.
那么我们怎样才能访问argv的四个元素呢
So how could we get access to not all four elements of argv
但只是一片argv吗
but just a slice of argv?
这实际上是Python和其他一些语言中的一个技术术语
And this is actually a technical term in Python and some other languages.
取列表的一部分意味着取列表的子集
To take a slice of a list means to take a subset of it
也许是从头开始 也许是中间 也许是结尾
maybe from the beginning, maybe the middle, maybe the end.
但切片是数据结构（如列表）的子集
But a slice is a subset of a data structure like a list.
那么 我实际上是如何用代码来实现的呢？
Well, how do I actually do this in code?
在Python中
Well, in Python, it's actually very easy to take a slice
一个列表是它的子集
of a list that is a subset thereof.
你可以简单地这样做
You can simply do this.
在列表名称（本例中为sys.argv）的末尾 可以使用方括号
At the end of the list name, sys.argv in this case, you can use square brackets.
然后在那些方括号里 你可以
And then in those square brackets, you can
指定要保留的列表的开始和结束
specify the start and the end of the list that you want to retain.
我想从元素1开始 而不是零
I want to start at element1, not zero.
我想从element1开始 然后一直到最后
I want to start at element1, and I want to just go to the end.
所以我打算省略掉第二个数字
So I'm actually going to omit a second number altogether.
没有必要有第二个数字
It's not necessary to have a second number.
但我需要那个冒号因为它会给我列表的一部分
But I do need that colon because this is going to give me a slice of the list.
它会给我列表中的一部分
It's going to give me a slice of the list that
从位置1开始 而不是零
starts at location1, not zero.
冒号和空格的意思是
And the colon and then a blank just means
它会给我其他的一切
it's going to give me everything else.
所以这是等价的 切掉列表的第一个元素
So this is in equivalently going to slice off the first element of the list
给我一个新的名单 只包含这三个人的名字 而不是
and give me a new list that contains just those three human names, not
文件本身的名称
the name of the file itself.
让我再试一次
Let me try running this again.
我要运行name.py的Python David Carter Rongshin
I'm going to run Python of name.py, David Carter Rongshin.
希望这次 我能拿到三个而且只有三个名牌
This time hopefully, I'm going to get three and only three name tags,
按回车键
hitting Enter.
事实上 我现在已经做到了这一点
And indeed, I've done now just this.
因此 同样 使用一些相对简单的Python语法
So again, using some relatively simple syntax in Python,
我们可以使用方括号 而不仅仅是转到特定的元素 如bracket0
we can use square brackets not just to go to specific elements like bracket0
或括号1
or bracket1.
我们还可以获得列表的子集、列表的片段
We can also get subsets of the list, slices of the list
通过使用方括号来冒号某物 其中每一个
by doing bracket something colon something where each of those
有些东西是一个数字 无论是开始还是结束
some things is a number, the beginning or the end,
它们是可选的 取决于您是否
and they're optional depending on whether you
全部都要 或者只想要一些
want all of them or just some.
现在有任何关于这个版本的问题吗 它添加了循环和这些切片
Any questions now on this version, which adds the loop and these slices
使用这种新的语法？
with that new syntax?
听众：我们能从论点的结尾--论点向量开始切分吗？
AUDIENCE: Can we slice starting from the end of the argument-- argument vector?
大卫·马兰：你可以的
DAVID MALAN: You can.
你可以从自变量向量的末尾切分一些东西
You can slice something from the end of the argument vector.
这可能会让人有点震惊
And this might blow one's mind a little bit.
让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我们看看
Let's see.
让我继续 在最后做一个负的
Let me go ahead and do negative one at the end.
在这里使用负数并运行相同的命令
Using a negative number here and running the same command,
我们刚刚取消了荣申在这里收到的名牌
we've just uninvited Rongshin from receiving a name tag here.
所以如果你使用负数 它会产生这样的效果
So if you use a negative number, it has the effect
从列表的末尾开始向另一个方向计数
of counting in the other direction from the end of the list.
这是个好问题
A good question there.
其他问题现在在切片上 关于在sys.argv上循环？
Other questions now on slices, on looping over sys.argv?
观众：嗨 我记得很早的时候
AUDIENCE: Hi, so I remember very early on when
我们讨论的浮点值只有两位小数
we were talking about only having two decimal places in float value.
这是不是也是一样的 因为我们在0.2F上使用代码？
Is that in the same vein, like, because we use the code on 0.2F?
那是一回事吗？
Is that the same thing then?
为什么F会包括在0.2F中 而不是这里 当你只是
Why would the F be included then in the 0.2F as opposed to here when you just
有数字吗？
have the numbers?
大卫·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
DAVID MALAN: A really good question.
简而言之 背景很重要
And it's just the short answer's that context matters.
所以我们的键盘上只有这么多键
So there's only so many keys on our keyboard.
所以我们有时会用相同的符号来表示不同的东西
And so we sometimes use the same symbols for different things.
所以你所指的是格式码
So what you're alluding to is the format code
在用于实际使用冒号、使用句点来格式化数字的F字符串中
in an F string for actually formatting a number using a colon, using a period,
使用数字、使用字母F等等
using a number, using the letter F and so forth.
这是Python的F字符串特性所特有的
And that is very specific to the F string feature of Python.
这种情况与语法本身无关
This case has nothing to do with any of that syntax per se.
这只是在不同的上下文中使用冒号
This is just using a colon in a different context
来解决这个问题 实现一个切片
to solve this problem to implement a slice.
Python的作者可以选择另一个符号
The authors of Python could have chosen another symbol.
但老实说 看着我的键盘
But honestly looking down at my keyboard here,
我们没有那么多容易打字的选择
we don't have that many to choose from that are easy to type.
有时候它们有不同的含义
So sometimes they have different meanings.
也是个好问题
A good question as well.
现在请允许我提议 我们进一步
Allow me to propose now, that we take things further
不再只使用那些模块 那些Python
and move away from using only those modules, those libraries that Python
来谈论更普遍的软件包
comes with to talk about more generally packages that exist.
Python如今如此流行和强大的原因之一是
One of the reasons that Python is so popular and powerful these days
有很多第三方库
is that there's a lot of third-party libraries
也就是所谓的包裹
out there as well, otherwise known as packages.
严格地说 Python本身有一个艺术术语
Strictly speaking, Python itself has a term of art
称为包 它本质上是一个模块
called a package, which is a module essentially
在一个文件夹中实现 不仅仅是一个文件 而是一个文件夹
that's implemented in a folder, not just a file but a folder.
但更一般地说 包是一个第三方库
But more generally, a package is a third-party library that you,
我可以安装在我们自己的Mac或PC或云服务器上
that I can install on our own Mac or PC or our cloud server
并获得更多功能
and gain access to even more functionality
其他人为我们实现的
that other people have implemented for us.
现在 你可以得到所有这些包裹的地点之一
Now, one of the locations you can get all of these packages
称为PYTI网站 Python包索引位于此URL
is called the PYTI website, the Python Package Index which lives at this URL
这里.
here.
这是一个可以通过命令行搜索的网站
And this is a website that is searchable via the command line,
也可以通过网络下载和安装
as well as via the web, that allows you to download and install
各种各样的包裹
all sorts of packages.
即使是CS50也有一些自己的服务包
Even CS50 has some of its own packages in services like these.
现在 有一个有趣的 这是一个倒退到一个命令
Now, there's a fun one out there that's a throwback to a command that's
在命令行环境中已经存在了很多年 叫做cowsay
been around for years in command line environments called cowsay.
Cowsay是Python中的一个包 它允许你让一头牛说些什么
Cowsay is a package in Python that allows you to have a cow say something
在你的屏幕上
on your screen.
如果你有兴趣阅读它 它自己的文档
If curious to read up on it, its own documentation
在pi.py.org上 特别是这里的这个URL
is on pi.py.org specifically at this URL here.
但是 您实际上是如何将该包输入您的系统的呢？
But how do you actually get the package into your system?
从技术上讲 你可以想办法下载这个文件
Well, technically, you could figure out how to download the file
或许还可以将其解压 放到Mac或PC上的正确位置
and maybe unzip it and put it into the right location on your Mac or PC.
但如今 许多语言 其中包括Python
But nowadays, a lot of languages, Python among them,
有所谓的自己的包管理器
has what's called its own package manager.
这里的这个叫pip 它只是一个
This one here called pip which is just one.
所以PIP是一个程序 通常是随Python本身一起提供的
So pip is a program that generally comes with Python itself, nowadays,
允许您在自己的Mac或PC上安装程序包
that allows you to install packages onto your own Macs or PCs
或云环境 只需运行一条命令
or cloud environment by just running a command.
然后 瞧 您可以访问一个全新的Python库
And then voila, you have access to a whole new library in Python
这并不是随Python本身一起提供的
that didn't come with Python itself.
但现在它可以在您的系统上为您提供
But now it's available on your system for you.
让我们回到这里的VS代码
Let's go back to VS Code here.
在我的终端窗口中 我将继续输入pip installcosay
And in my terminal window, I'm going to go ahead and type pip install cowsay.
现在 这是怎么回事？
Now, what's going on here?
Pip是命令 是包管理器
Pip is the command, the package manager.
我想安装什么程序包？
And I want to install what package?
这个套餐叫做牛仔套餐
The package called cowsay.
我将继续并在这里按Enter键
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter here.
经过一点点的产出 它已经成功地安装了COROWAY
And after a little bit of output, it has successfully installed cowsay.
那么 这意味着什么呢？
Now, what does that mean?
这意味着我现在可以着手将其导入到我自己的代码中
That means I can now go about importing this into my own code.
好吧 让我们继续下去 看看这意味着什么
Well, let's go ahead and see what this means.
因此 让我们继续创建一个名为say.py的新文件
So let me go ahead and create a new file with code called say.py
因为我想在屏幕上说点什么
because I want something to be said on the screen.
在我的新选项卡中 我将继续导入牛肝菌
And in my new tab here, I'm going to go ahead and import cowsay,
现在大概已经安装好了
which presumably is now installed.
我现在也要导入系统 因为我
I'm now going to import sys as well because I'd
我想在此程序中使用一些命令行参数
like to use some command line arguments in this program
这样我就能快点跑了
just so that I can run it quickly.
而且不使用输入函数 我就可以获得用户名
And without using the input function, I can get the user's name
立即从提示符开始
immediately from the prompt.
让我继续做这件事
And let me go ahead and do this.
这一次 我将主动执行一些错误检查
I'm going to do a bit of error checking proactively this time.
而不是使用小于或大于 我是
And rather than use less than or greater than, I'm
这一次将说明sys.argv的长度是否等于2
this time going to say if the length of sys.argv does equal 2.
所以如果这个人只是被提供了名字
So if the human is provided just the name
以及他们自己的名字 我们就可以开始了
of the program and their own first name, we're good to go.
我将执行以下操作
I'm going to do the following.
我将在包中调用一个名为cow的函数 该函数名为cowsay
I'm going to call a function called COW in the package called cowsay.
我将传入一个字符串 你好 逗号
And I'm going to pass in a string, hello, comma.
然后像过去一样 我将只传递一个字符串
And then as in the past, I'm going to pass in just one string
因为根据它的文件 它不像印刷品
because according to its documentation, it's not like print.
我不能用逗号这个 逗号那个
I can't pass in comma this, comma that.
我只能传入一个字符串
I can only pass in one string.
所以我将把它与sys.argv bracket1的内容连接起来
So I'm going to concatenate it the contents of sys.argv, bracket1.
只要我在这个程序的名字后面输入我的名字David
So long as then I type in my name David after the name of this program,
它应该以sys.argv1结束 在这种情况下 代码的第5行
it should end up in sys.argv1 in which case, this line five of code
应该把Hello和我的名字连接起来 中间加一个空格
should concatenate hello with my name with a space in between.
很明显 一头牛会这么说
And apparently, a cow is going to say it.
所以让我们看看这里会发生什么
So let's see what happens here.
让我继续清除我的屏幕并增加
Let me go ahead and clear my screen and increase
我的终端窗口的大小
the size of my terminal window.
让我继续运行say.py的Python 然后输入我的名字David并回车
Let me go ahead and run Python of say.py and type my name David and Enter.
有一个节目叫“牛仔”
There is the program called cowsay.
它确实让一头牛在屏幕上说了些什么
It literally has a cow say something on the screen.
这是对过去一个节目的倒退
And this is a throwback to a program from yesteryear
这往往伴随着许多系统
that tended to come with a lot of systems.
这也被称为ASCII ART
This is otherwise known as ASCII art.
这是一种只使用键盘上的按键的文本方式
It's a textual way using just keys on your keyboard
在屏幕上打印各种图片
to print pictures of sorts on the screen.
现在 我们真的可以走进兔子洞了
Now, we can really go down the rabbit hole here.
这样做的学术价值值得怀疑
And there's questionable academic value of doing so.
所以我只会这么做一次
So I'll do so just once.
原来 COWSAY套餐还附带了其他功能
Turns out the cowsay package comes with other functions as well.
例如 霸王龙就是其中的一个功能
One of those functions, for instance, is T-Rex.
如果我现在增加终端窗口的大小
And if I now increase the size of my terminal window,
我们可能会看到我们将如何处理这件事
we'll perhaps see where we're going with this.
现在让我再运行一次 Say.py的Python
Let me now run again, Python of say.py.
这一次 让我不提供我的名字只是为了看看它是不是坏了
This time, let me not provide my name just to see if it's broken.
还是可以的 因为我们有如果的条件
It's still OK because we have that if condition
如果sys.argv的长度等于等于2并且仅当它等于等于2时
if the length of sys.argv equals equals 2 and only if it equals equals 2,
我们做任何事情
do we do anything.
所以我们什么都没看到
That's why we're not seeing anything here.
让我继续合作吧 大卫 say.py
Let me go ahead and cooperate now, say.py space David.
它不再是一头牛了
And it's no longer a cow.
但如果我把屏幕拉远一只霸王龙
But if I zoom out on my screen, a T-Rex.
为什么要这样？
Why?
只是因为这些是你一旦知道如何编程就可以做的事情
Just because these are the things you can do once you know how to program.
你甚至可以把它们打包起来 让其他人免费使用
You can even package them up and make them freely available to others
开源软件
as open source software.
对我们来说 这是一个更普遍的特征的展示
For us, it's demonstrative of a feature more generally here
即能够安装这些第三方软件包
namely being able to install these third-party packages and how
你可以在Python中这样做
you might do so in Python.
现在 我把这个留在屏幕上一会儿
Now, I'll leave this up on the screen for a moment
看看有没有关于奶牛的问题
and see if there's any questions about cows
或者霸王龙的或者更普遍的包裹
or Tyrannosaurus rex's or packages more generally.
我真的有资格和他们中的一个说话
I'm really qualified to speak to just one of those.
观众：嗨 我有两个问题
AUDIENCE: Hi, I've got two questions it's a bit earlier than what's
应该是的
supposed to be.
所以第一个问题是
So the first question is the packages that you're
在程序中调用 它们是否相同
calling to use in the program, are they the same
比如说 Java的东西 就像调用类 Java文件一样
as, let's say, something Java the same as calling a class, a Java file
为了使用它的功能？
in order to use its functions?
我的第二个问题是 使用命令行的实际目的是什么
And my second question is, what's the actual purpose of using command line
因为这不是最好的方法 就像你说的
arguments as you used because is not really the best way to, as you say,
对用户友好 比如说
be user friendly where as in let's say the person who's
使用这个程序的人不知道他们想要什么--
using the program doesn't know what they want--
程序在问他们什么
what the program's asking them?
大卫·马兰：问得好
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
第一个关于与Java、Python包比较的问题
The first question about the comparison with Java, Python packages
类似于Java包 你有一些东西
are similar to Java packages where you have something.something.something
在你的程序的顶部
at the top of your program that gives you
访问类或其他东西
access to a class or something else.
Python本身支持类
Python itself supports classes.
更多关于那些在路上
More on those down the road.
你可以在Python中做与Java非常相似的事情
And you can do very similar things in Python as you can do with Java.
但这里的类比实际上是Python包到Java包
But the analog really is Python packages to Java packages here.
至于命令行参数 您提出了一个很好的问题
As for command line arguments, you ask a good question.
我们为什么要使用它们 特别是如果它们确实是用户友好的呢？
Why do we use them, especially if they are literally user friendly?
他们对人们的使用不太友好
They're a little less user friendly to people
老实说 他们不在这个变速箱里
who aren't in this Zoom to be honest.
你和我随着我们对编程的了解越来越多
You and I as we learn more and more about programming
以及更多关于命令行参数的信息 我敢说
and more about command line arguments, I daresay
我们会变得更适应和照顾
we'll become more comfortable with and tend
更喜欢使用这些命令行自定义命令的功能
to prefer the ability to customize commands using these command line
争论
arguments.
为什么？
Why?
生产力
Productivity.
它往往会让你更快 因为你得到了
It tends to make you faster because you get
养成了一种习惯 即确切地知道你是如何
into the habit of knowing exactly how you
无需手动回答问题即可配置您的软件
can configure your software without having to manually answer questions.
这就是一个很好的例子
And case in point.
在这段时间里 我们一直在运行某个.py版本的Python
All of this time have we been running Python of something.py.
你可以想象不会这样做
You could imagine not doing that.
您可以想象只输入Python 然后按Enter键
You can imagine typing only Python, hitting Enter.
然后系统会提示您输入要运行的文件的名称
And then you're prompted for the name of the file you want to run.
所以你输入一些东西.py 然后它就会运行
So you type in something.py, and then it runs.
没什么大不了的 但我认为随着时间的推移 你是
Not a big deal, but I would argue that over time, you're
我会对TDM感到有点厌倦的
going to get a little tired of that TDM.
你会更喜欢自动操作
And you would much prefer to just automate
一次又一次的命令 尤其是一些小的方便
the command again and again and again, especially with little conveniences
比如能够在你的键盘历史记录中上下敲击
like being able to hit up and down in your keyboard history
以便重新运行相同命令
so as to rerun those same command.
如果你从这样的课堂上走出来 自动化也很重要
Automation is big too if you emerge from a class like this
并开始使用Python自动化流程
and start using Python to automate processes
在工作或个人项目等方面
at work or for personal projects or the like,
能够在一行中指定所有输入
the ability to specify all of your inputs on the one line
只是意味着你可以更快地完成工作
just means you can get work done more quickly.
所以毫不费力 绝对是
So hands down, absolutely.
使用命令行参数是系统的一项更神秘的功能
Using command line arguments is a more arcane feature of systems
我们中的大多数人不再那么熟悉 因为
that most of us are no longer as familiar with because
Windows和Mac OS以及其他操作系统的
of Windows and Mac OS and other operating systems that
有按钮、图形用户界面和菜单
have buttons and GUIs and menus.
但你对编程的适应程度越高
But the more comfortable you get with programming,
我敢说 您越倾向于使用这些功能 因为它们
I daresay the more you will tend to prefer these capabilities because they
让你做事更快
allow you to do things more quickly.
话虽如此 请允许我提议我们转向 然而
With that said, allow me to propose that we take a turn toward, yet,
另一个特别受欢迎的软件包
another package that's particularly popular and just as easy
来安装所有的API
to install all toward an end of using APIs.
API并不是Python特有的
Now, APIs are not something that's Python-specific.
更一般地 API是应用程序编程接口
More generally, an API is an application programming interface.
它可以引用Python文件和函数
And it can refer to Python files and functions.
但通常 API实际上指的是第三方服务
But often, APIs really refer to third-party services
你和我可以写代码和它对话
that you and I can write code that talk to.
许多API 但不是全部 这些天生活在互联网上
Many APIs, but not all, live on the internet these days
所以只要你有一个浏览器
so that so long as you have a browser or so long
如果你有一些Python编程或编程的经验
as you have some experience with Python programming or programming
在任何语言中 您都可以编写实际上假装是浏览器的代码
in any language, you can write code that in effect pretends to be a browser,
连接到服务器上的第三方API
connects to that third-party API on a server,
然后下载一些数据 你可以把它们合并到你自己的程序中
and download some data that you can then incorporate into your own program.
现在 你是怎么做到的？
Now, how do you do this?
Python有一个非常流行的包
Well, Python has a very popular package that you
可以通过pip安装所谓的请求
can install via pip called requests.
requests库允许您发出web请求
The requests library allows you to make web request,
Internet请求基本上使用Python代码
internet request using Python code essentially
就像你自己是一个浏览器
as though you were a browser yourself.
因此 您可以自动检索URL
You can automate, therefore, the retrieval of URLs
以HTTP或HTTPS开头
that start with HTTP or HTTPS.
这个库的文档是这样的URL
The documentation for this library is that a URL like this,
但它也可以在命令行中安装
but it too can be installed at the command line.
即使是第三方
And even though it's third party, it's one
Python中最流行和最常用的包
of the most popular and commonly used packages out there in Python.
这也是Python如此受欢迎的原因之一
And this too is one of the reasons again that Python is so popular.
解决问题的方法太多了
There's just so many solutions to problems
你和我已经或将要
that you and I have or are invariably going to have
when we write写projects项目of our own拥有.
when we write projects of our own.
这是一个充满活力的生态系统 一个充满活力的社区
There's just a really vibrant ecosystem, a really vibrant community
开源软件 对我们来说很容易安装
of open source software that's that easy for us to install.
让我回到我的终端窗口现在运行
Let me go back to my terminal window now and run
PIP安装请求 以便在我自己的系统上安装此程序包
pip install requests in order to install this package on my own system.
在几行输出之后 我将看到它已成功安装
And after some lines of output, I'll see that it's successfully installed.
现在 让我们继续在这里创建一个新文件
Now, let's go ahead and create a new file here.
例如 itunes.py
For instance, itunes.py.
事实证明 苹果有自己的iTunes服务API
It turns out that Apple has its own API for their iTunes service.
为您提供功能的软件
The software that provides you with the ability
下载和搜索音乐和歌曲以及其他信息
to download and search for music and songs and other information as well.
事实证明--让我回到我的电脑上
And it turns out that-- let me go back over to my computer
在这里打开一个类似Chrome的浏览器
here and open up a browser like Chrome.
让我继续访问这个URL
And let me go ahead and visit this URL here,
Https://itunes.apple.com/search?entity=song&amp；limit=1&amp；term=weezer.
https://itunes.apple.com/ search?entity=song&amp;limit=1&amp;term=weezer.
搜索？Entity=Song&amp；Limit=1&amp；Term=Weezer
Search?entity=song&amp; limit=1&amp;term=weezer.
现在 我通过阅读以下内容手动构建了这个URL
Now, I constructed this URL manually by reading
苹果API的文档--
the documentation for Apple's API--
ITune的应用程序编程接口
application programming interface for iTune.
他们告诉我 如果我想搜索关于歌曲的信息
And what they told me is that if I want to search for information about songs
在他们数据库中 我应该指定实体
in their database, I should specify entity
等于歌曲 所以歌曲而不是专辑或艺术家或类似的东西
equals song so that songs and not albums or artists or something like that.
如果我只想拿回一首歌的信息
If I just want to get back information on one song,
我将提供等于1的限制
I'm going to provide limit equals 1.
如果我要找的乐队 艺术家是Weezer
And if the band I want to search for, the artist is Weezer,
我应该指定术语等于Weezer
I should specify term equals Weezer.
因此 如果我继续按Enter键并访问此URL
So with this, if I go ahead and hit Enter and visit this URL,
实际上 我在Mac上的下载文件夹中看到了一个文本文件
I actually end up with a text file in my Downloads folder on my Mac.
如果我继续打开浏览器刚刚下载文本文件
If I go ahead and open that text file that my browser just downloaded,
我们将在这里看到所有这些文本 乍一看
we'll see all of this text here, which at first glance
可能看起来有点神秘 但它实际上遵循了一个模式
might look a bit cryptic, but it actually follows a pattern.
请注意开头的花括号 并注意以下内容
Notice this curly brace at the start and notice this
末尾有一个闭合的花括号
closed curly brace at the end.
注意这里的左方括号和这里的闭方括号
Notice this open square bracket here and notice this closed square bracket here.
在这些语法之间有
And in between those pieces of syntax are
一大堆字符串和值
a whole bunch of strings and values.
事实上 这是一大堆键值对
In fact, a whole bunch of key value pairs.
我们现在看到的是一种标准的文本格式 叫做JSON
What we're looking at here is a standard text format known as JSON--
JavaScript对象表示法 是的 在技术上是相关的
JavaScript Object Notation, which yes, is technically related to yet,
另一种编程语言叫做JavaScript
another programming language called JavaScript.
但JSON本身现在通常被用于
But JSON itself is typically used nowadays
作为在计算机之间交换数据的语言无关格式
as a language agnostic format for exchanging data between computers.
所谓语言无关 我的意思是你不必使用JavaScript
By language agnostic, I mean you don't have to use JavaScript.
您可以使用Python或任何其他语言来读取或编写JSON
You can use Python or any other language to read JSON or write it as well.
它是一种完全基于文本的格式
And it's a completely text-based format, which
意味着如果我用浏览器访问该URL
means that if I visit that URL with my browser, what gets downloaded
只是一堆文字
is just a bunch of text.
但该文本是用花括号以标准方式格式化的
But that text is formatted in a standard way using curly braces
并使用引号和一些冒号进行方括号 最终包含
and square bracket using quotes and some colons that ultimately contains
至少苹果数据库中关于Weezer歌曲的所有信息
all of the information in Apple's database on Weezer's song, at least,
第一个是因为我把它限制在他们数据库里的一个
the first one because I limited it to one in their database.
这是一个API 一个应用程序编程接口
And that's an API, an application programming interface.
一种机制 使我可以访问其他人的服务器上的数据
A mechanism whereby I can access data on someone else's server
并以某种方式将其整合到我自己的程序中
and somehow integrate it into my own program.
当然 我的浏览器Chrome不是我写的
Now, of course, my browser, Chrome, is not something I wrote.
我应该写一些Python代码
I should actually write some Python code that perhaps pretends
成为一个浏览器来获取同样的数据
to be a browser to grab this same data.
我们就这么做吧
So let's do that.
让我们回到VS Code
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我用代码写一个程序 itunes.py
And let me write a program with code, itunes.py.
我们将编写一些代码 通过这些代码 我可以使用iTunes API
And we're going to write some code via which I can then use the iTunes API
反过来 Python可以获取我想要的任何乐队的信息
and in turn, Python to get information about any band that I might want.
我将在这里首先导入请求
I'm going to go here and import first the requests
库 我之前安装它是为了发出那些HTTP请求
library, which I installed earlier in order to make those HTTP requests.
我将继续导入sys库 通过它
I'm going to go ahead and import the sys library via which I'll have the ability
使用命令行参数 如波段的规格
to use command line arguments like specification of the band
如果不是威瑟的话我也要找
that I want to search for if not Weezer.
然后在这里 我将继续插入一些错误检查
And then down here, I'm going to go ahead and insert some error checking
如果sys.argv的长度不等于--
to say if the length of sys.argv does not equal to--
因此 如果用户不向我提供文件名
so if the user does not provide me with the name of the file
他们想要竞选和一个乐队的名字 就这样 你知道吗
they want to run and the name of a band, and that's it, you know what.
让我们先走一步 然后暂时离开
Let's just go ahead and exit for now.
我可以提供一个更具解释性的信息
I could provide a more explanatory message.
但现在 我会让事情变得简单
But for now, I'm going to keep things simple
提前退出程序 这样我以后就可以信任了
and just exit the program prematurely so that I can trust hereafter
那个sys.argv有我想要的东西
that sys.argv has what I want.
现在 我有机会使用请求库编写
And now, I have the opportunity to use the requests library to write
一些有效地伪装的Python代码
some Python code that effectively is pretending
成为Web浏览器 以便连接到相同的HTTPS
to be a web browser so as to connect to that same HTTPS
苹果自己的服务器上的URL
URL on Apple's own server.
现在我已经保证用户已经输入了
So now that I've guaranteed that the user has typed in
提示时 不仅要输入文件名 还要输入波段名称
not just the name of the file, but also the name of a band at the prompt
给我一个sys.argv的长度为2 让我们继续
giving me a length of two for sys.argv, let's go ahead
并执行请求股票 这是请求包中的一个函数
and execute request stockget, which is a function inside of the request package
从字面上讲 这将从服务器获得一些响应
that will literally get some response from a server.
而我想要获取的URL与之前完全相同
And the URL that I want to get is the exactly the same as before.
Https://itunes.apple.com/搜索？实体=歌曲；限制=1(&A；
https://itunes.apple.com/ search?entity=song&amp; limit=1&amp;
术语=以前的除草机
term=previouslyweezer.
但让我们让这个节目更具互动性
But let's make this program a little interactive
并且实际上允许用户在命令行中指定
and actually allow the human to specify at the command line what
他们想要寻找的艺术家
artists they'd like to search for.
所以我要提前结束我的报价
So I'm going to go ahead and close my quote early and just
像过去一样使用串联运算符sys.argv bracket1进行追加
append using the concatenation operator as in the past, sys.argv bracket1.
现在 它实际上很好地存储了响应
And now, it actually be nice to store the response
从服务器的变量中
from the server in a variable.
所以我要继续说 回答等于
So I'm going to go ahead and say response equals
并存储所有返回的响应
and to store all of the response that comes back
来自服务器的名为Response的变量中
from the server in a variable called response.
现在 我想要了解的是
Down here now, I'd like to just understand
服务器返回给我的是什么 以确保我知道下一步如何继续
what the server's returning to me to make sure I know how next to proceed.
所以这还不会很美好
So this isn't going to be very pretty yet.
但我要把答案打印出来 json
But I'm going to go and print out response.json,
它可以确保我得到的数据在屏幕上被格式化
which ensures that the data I'm getting back is formatted on my screen
就是JSON 和我们在屏幕上看到的一样的文本格式
as exactly that, JSON, the same text format as we saw on my screen.
它还不是一个有用的程序
It's not a useful program yet.
我真的只是一路上学习
I'm really just learning along the way.
但是现在让我继续增加终端窗口的大小
But let me go ahead now and increase the size of my terminal window
运行itunes.py的Python 输入一个乐队的名字 比如Weezer
and run Python of itunes.py and type in the name of a band like Weezer
然后按回车键
and hit Enter.
我们在屏幕上看到的格式几乎相同
And what we see on the screen formatted almost the same
与之前的文本完全相同
as before is exactly that same text.
但你会看到这已经标准化了
But what you'll see here is that this has been standardized now
Python字典
as a Python dictionary.
实际上 苹果返回的是一个JSON响应
What indeed Apple's returning is technically a JSON response,
JavaScript对象表示法
JavaScript Object Notation.
但是Python 请求库正在转换它
But Python, the request library is converting it
到Python字典 它碰巧使用了非常巧合的 几乎
to a Python dictionary which happens to use wonderfully coincidentally, almost
相同的语法
the same syntax.
它在这里用花括号表示字典
It uses curly braces to represent the dictionary here
和一个右花括号来表示它的结尾
and a close curly brace to represent the end of it here.
对于其中的任何列表 它在此处使用方括号
For any lists therein, it uses a square bracket here
和一个封闭的方括号
and a closed square bracket down here.
它使用了引号--这里是单引号 或者等效的双引号
It uses quotes-- single quotes in this case or equivalently double quotes
来表示字典中的键
to represent the keys in that dictionary.
在冒号之后 它存储该键的值
And after a colon, it stores the value of that key.
所以你会看到我们确实有一个结果计数键 它的值是1
And so you'll see that indeed we have a result count key whose value is 1,
但是还有一个更有趣的Result键 叫做results
but then a more interesting Result key called results whose
值是整个数据列表
value is this entire list of data.
老实说 这是一个很大的文本块
Now, honestly, this is such a big blob of text
我得花很长时间才能理解我所看到的
that it's going to take me forever to wrap my mind around what I'm seeing.
所以让我暂时建议我们使用Python中的另一个库
So let me propose temporarily we use another library in Python that
可以让我更清晰地格式化数据
will allow me to format my data a little more cleanly.
原来Python还附带了一个特殊的库
It turns out that Python also comes with a special library called
JSON允许您操作JSON数据
JSON that allows you to manipulate JSON data
甚至只是打印出来
and even just printy print it that is formatted in a way that's going to be
更容易让你我理解
way easier for you and I to understand.
让我回到我的代码
So let me go back to my code here.
让我缩小我的终端窗口
Let me shrink my terminal window.
让我再一次暂时地建议我们这样做
And let me propose that just temporarily again we do this.
让我导入这个额外的库JSON 它是随Python一起提供的
Let me import this additional library, JSON, which comes with Python.
所以我不需要使用pip手动安装它
So I don't need to install it manually with pip.
现在让我继续 而不仅仅是打印出来
And let me go ahead now and not just print out
响应.json 这是一大团难以理解的文本
response.json which was that big blob of hard-to-understand text.
让我们继续使用另一个函数 这里称为json.dups
Let me go ahead and use one other function here called json.dumps
用于转储字符串 并传递给响应.json返回的函数
for dump string and pass to that function that response.json return
价值
value.
所以 我再一次介绍另一个函数
So again, I'm just introducing another function
我认为他一生的目标都是漂亮的印刷品
who I claim has a purpose in life of pretty printing,
在屏幕上巧妙地格式化完全相同的信息
nicely formatting on the screen the exact same information.
我从以前做过这件事的文件中知道了这一点
And I know this from the documentation having done this before.
但我想让东西缩进得很好
But I'd like things to be nicely indented.
根据文档 如果我传入一个命名参数缩进
And according to the documentation, if I pass in a named parameter of indent
等于2 这将使所有内容缩进至少两个空格
equals 2, that's going to indent everything at least two spaces.
我可以做四个或其他的事情
I could do four or something else.
但这将足以帮助我思考什么
But it's going to be enough to help me wrap my mind around what
数据是我要回来了
the data is I'm getting back.
因为再说一次 我只是和你一起学习
Because again, I'm just learning along with you.
因此 让我再次增加终端窗口的大小
So let me increase the size of my terminal window again.
让我运行itunes.py的Python
Let me run Python of itunes.py.
再一次 让我们搜索Weezer并按Enter键
And again, let's search for Weezer and hit Enter.
现在 注意到它仍然有一点神秘
And now, notice it's still a little bit cryptic
因为这里发生了很多事情
because there's a lot going on here.
但我的天啊 我现在完全可以更容易地阅读这个了
But my gosh, I can totally read this more easily now.
请注意 现在我仍然看到第一个大括号 这意味着嘿
Notice now that I still see the first curly brace, which means hey,
这是一本用Python语言编写的词典
this is a dictionary in Python.
键和值的集合
A collection of keys and values.
第一个键称为结果计数
The first key is called result count.
现在恰好用双引号显示
It happens to be displayed in double quotes now.
但这只是一个格式问题
But that's just an issue of formatting.
只要我们是一致的 就可以是双人或单人
It could be double or single so long as we're consistent.
该密钥的值为1
The value of that key is one.
为什么？
Why?
嗯 我告诉URL将回复限制在一首Weezer歌曲上
Well, I told the URL to only limit the responses to one Weezer song
所以我得到了一个1的结果集
so I've gotten a result set of one.
如果我增加这个限制 我可能会得到更多
If I increase that limit, I could probably get more.
那么 这个响应中有趣的部分实际上就是数据本身
Then the interesting part of this response is really the data itself.
请注意 在这里的结果键中 有一个非常大的值
Notice in the results key here, there's a really big value.
如方括号所示 该值是一个Python列表
The value is a Python list as implied by this square bracket.
这张单子里有什么？
What does this list contain?
嗯 我从之前的浏览中知道 这里面有一本词典
Well, I know from skimming it earlier that this contains one dictionary.
这就是为什么我们在这里看到另一个花括号
And that's why we see another curly brace here.
所以 再说一次 如果事情变得更复杂
So again, if this gets a little more complicated,
请记住 字典只是键值对的集合
keep in mind that a dictionary is just a collection of key value pairs.
而Python使用大括号来表示这一点
And Python uses curly braces to indicate as much.
买一本词典是完全合理的
It is perfectly reasonable for a dictionary
如果某个键本身的值在另一个词典中
to be inside of another dictionary if the value of some key itself
是另一本词典
is another dictionary.
所以这是一个常见的范例
So this is a common paradigm.
尽管这可能看起来有点神秘
And even though it might seem a bit cryptic,
它只是允许我们将更多的键与更多的值相关联
it's just something that allows us to associate more keys with more value.
现在 这些信息中的大部分 我可能并不关心
Now, most of this information, I probably don't care about.
例如 根据苹果公司的说法 Weezer的唯一标识符
For instance, according to Apple, the unique identifier for Weezer
显然是115,234
is apparently 115,234.
如果我要创建自己的数据库 这可能会很有用
That might be useful if I'm making my own database
我希望这是可搜索的
and I want this to be searchable.
但为了今天的目的 我只关心赛道的名字
But for today's purposes, all I care about is the name of the track,
也称为轨道名称作为关键点
otherwise called track name as key.
第一首歌 也是唯一一首歌 因为我们把它限制在一首
And the first song and only song because we limited it to one
我们从iTunes回来的是这首歌
that we got back from iTunes here is the song
你可能知道威泽叫“不是这样说”
that you might know by Weezer called Say It Ain't So.
现在 我有了一点线索 如果我的目标是实现一个计划
So now, I have a bit of a clue if my goal here is to implement a program
名为itunes.py 它不仅转储来自服务器的响应
called itunes.py that doesn't just dump the response from the server,
诚然 这是非常神秘的--
which is admittedly very cryptic--
但要打印出iTunes为Weezer乐队准备的所有歌曲
but to print out all of the songs that iTunes has for the band called Weezer,
也许我可以以某种方式重复一下
maybe I can iterate over this somehow.
所以 让我回顾一下
So let me backtrack.
这是关键呼叫跟踪名称
Here's the key call track name.
在词典中 它就是这里结果的价值
It is inside of a dictionary that is the value of results here.
那么 我该如何着手拿到这个呢？
So how can I go about getting this?
好吧 让我来试试这个
Well, let me go ahead and try this.
让我继续缩小我的终端窗口
Let me go ahead and shrink my terminal window back down
现在让我为最后一次盛大的表演做最后的提议
and let me propose now for one final flourish.
我们不会只是懒洋洋地把内容打印出来
We don't just lazily print out the contents
因为这对任何人来说都不有趣或不美观
of that response because that's not interesting or pretty for anyone.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
让我们继续创建一个新变量
Let me go ahead and create a new variable
仅为讨论起见 将对象称为O
just for the sake of discussion called O for object.
我将继续调用o等于Response.json
And I'm going to go ahead and call o equals response.json just
要专门将该JSON响应存储在名为o的变量中
to store that JSON response specifically in a variable called o,
但我可以给它起任何我想要的名字
but I could name it anything I want.
现在 我要做这件事
And now, I'm going to do this.
对于该对象的键中的每个名为Results的结果
For each result in that object's key called results,
继续打印结果的曲目名称
go ahead and print out that result's track name.
请注意 我使用的是完全相同的大写
And notice I have used exactly the same capitalization.
曲目名称为大写N 结果全部为小写
Track name has a capital N. Result is all lowercase.
在我们运行实际的程序之前 让我回顾一下
And let me rewind before we run the actual program.
在第八行中 我们发出了一个HTTP请求
In line eight, we are making an HTTP request
像你我一样在服务器上使用Python作为人类输入的URL
using Python to the server just like you and I as humans type URLs
进入浏览器 然后按Enter键
into a browser and hit Enter.
这是等效于Python的代码
This is the Python equivalent thereof.
然后我在第10行 从那个变量中获取
I am then on line 10 just grabbing from that variable that
包含服务器的响应 即我关心的JSON对象
contains the server's response, the JSON object that I care about.
在最上面和最下面的花括号之间的东西
The thing between those curly braces at the very top and the bottom.
而是因为我们四处打听 因为我
But because we've poked around and because I
读了前面的文档 我知道该对象
read the documentation earlier, I know that that object
有一个名为Results的键
has a key called results.
而结果关键又是一个列表
And that results key again is a list.
现在 这份名单上只有一首歌
Now, at the moment, that list contains only one song,
我不是这么说的 因为我的回答只有一个
Say It Ain't So, because I limited my response to one.
但即便如此 我的循环还是会起作用的
But even so, my loop will work.
它只会迭代一次
It's just going to iterate once.
每次通过这个循环 它都会
And each time through that loop, it's going
若要打印当前结果的曲目名称 请执行以下操作
to print the current result's track name.
如果我想让这件事更有趣
If I want to make this even more interesting,
现在让我将这个限制从1更改为50
let me change this limit now from 1 to 50
所以我至少可以取回50个曲目名称
so I'll at least get back 50 track names instead.
现在让我继续并再次增加我的终端的大小
Let me go ahead now and increase the size of my terminal once more
现在继续并再次运行itunes.py的Python搜索
and go ahead now and run Python of itunes.py searching again
对于像威兹这样的乐队来说
for a band like Weezer.
现在我们开始吧
And here we go.
瞧 iTunes为Weezer准备了50首歌
And voila, there are 50 songs that iTunes has for Weezer.
如果我们向上滚动到顶部
And if we scroll back up to the top here,
我们会看到 第一个人 确实 也不是这样说的
we'll see that the very first one there is, indeed, Say It Ain't So.
但现在 我们被解开了--
But now, we got Undone--
毛衣之歌 巴迪·霍莉
The Sweater Song, Buddy Holly.
显然 另一首《Say It Ain Not》可能也是如此
Apparently another rendition of Say It Ain't So perhaps
从另一张专辑 另一张巴迪·霍利未完成 我的名字是乔纳斯 等等
from another album, another Buddy Holly undone, my name is Jonas, and so forth.
现在关于这个将Python与现实世界相结合的程序的问题
Questions now on this program which integrates Python with a real world
第三方API？
third party API?
观众：是的 嗨
AUDIENCE: Yeah, hi.
我们可以使用Break而不是Syst.Exit吗？
Can we use break instead of system.exit?
大卫·马兰：问得好 但不是
DAVID MALAN: Good question, but no.
Break Again用来打破我们之前看到的循环
Break again is used to break out of things like loops like we saw earlier.
使用Sys.Exit来突破整个程序本身
Sys.exit is used to break out of the whole program itself.
暂时使用BREAK FOR循环 并使用sys.exit终止
Use break for loops for now and use sys.exit to terminate
整个节目
the whole program.
问得好
Good question.
现在节目中的其他问题还有其他问题吗？
Other questions now on this program are others?
观众：我们从哪里带来了关键成果的名字？
AUDIENCE: From where we bring the name of the key results?
大卫·马兰：我们从哪里得到钥匙的名字？
DAVID MALAN: From where do we get the name of the key?
观众：结果本身
AUDIENCE: Results itself.
是啊 我们能不能更改结果 改名字？
Yeah, and can we change the results, the name?
大卫·马兰：你不能
DAVID MALAN: You cannot.
所以我们可以在我们的项目中
So we could in our program.
因此 明确地说 在JSON响应中返回的键
So the keys that come back in that JSON response, to be clear,
来自itunes.apple.com
come from iTunes.Apple.com.
一些工程师团队为我们决定了所有这些钥匙的名称
Some team of engineers decided for us what all of those keys would be called,
包括曲目名称、结果、结果计数以及其他所有内容
including track name, results, result count, and everything else.
你和我完全可以将这些相同的值存储在变量中
You and I can absolutely store those same values in variables
就像我在这里对O所做的 就像我在这里对Result所做的那样
just like I'm doing here with O, just like I'm doing here with result.
可以使用Python变量随心所欲地重命名这些关键点
You can rename those keys anything you want using Python variables.
但JSON响应来自该第三方服务器
But the JSON response is coming from that third party server.
其他问题
Other questions.
观众：是的 先生
AUDIENCE: Yes, sir.
因此 我有一个问题与牛仔套餐有关
So I have a question related to cowsay package.
就像是 是的
So like, yes.
那么 先生 它能提供什么样的ASCII图形呢？
So sir, what sort of ASCII graphics is it capable of putting?
DAVID MALAN：牛仔套餐
DAVID MALAN: The cowsay package.
我建议您参考幻灯片中的URL
I would refer you to the URL in the slides
因为这样更彻底
earlier if only because it's more thorough.
他们不仅有牛 还有霸王龙
They have not just cows, but Tyrannosaurus rex's
还有其他几种动物
and several other animals as well.
我要强调的是 这不是一个包 我怀疑
I should emphasize that this is not a package I suspect
你在现实世界中会用到很多东西
you will use much in the real world.
它实际上只是代表了
It's really just meant to be representative of the types of packages
你可以安装
you can install.
但是 请允许我参考文件 了解更多的情况
But allow me to refer to the documentation for what more is there.
但在表情符号出现之前 我们只有ASCII艺术 更不用说GIF和JPEG了
But ASCII art is all we had before there were emojis, let alone GIFs and JPEGs
和ping
and pings.
但这是考赛镇的不朽之作
But it's what's is immortalized in cowsay.
好 现在让我们回到Python的最后一个功能
Well, allow me to transition us back now to one final capability of Python which
就是你们自己有能力建立自己的图书馆
is that you yourselves have the ability to make your own libraries.
到目前为止 我们一直在编写一个
Up until now, we've been writing all of our functions in our one
文件 你好py和一切 因为.
file, Hello py and everything since.
现在我们已经介绍了Python中的模块 随机和统计
And now that we've introduced modules in Python, random and statistics,
我们可以导入Python自带的
we can import those that come with Python.
但这也是别人的代码
But that's other people's code as well.
我们现在已经使用pip 这个包管理器来安装
And we've now used pip, this package manager to install
系统中的第三方软件包
third-party packages as well in the system
使用别人的代码
and using other people's code still.
但是回到原点 如果你自己
But to come full circle, what if you yourself
发现自己一次又一次地实现相同的功能
find yourself implementing the same kinds of functions again and again,
或者你发现自己打开了旧的程序
or you find yourself opening up old programs,
复制并粘贴你写的代码到新程序中
copying and pasting code you wrote into new programs
因为你又遇到了同样的问题
because you have the same problem yet again?
一个好的做法是以某种方式将您不断重用的代码捆绑起来
A good practice would be to somehow bundle up that code you keep reusing
创建你自己的Python模块或包
and make your own Python module or package.
您可以将其保存在您自己的Mac或PC或云服务器上
You can keep it local on your own Mac or PC or cloud server.
或者你可以把它捆起来
Or you can go through the steps of actually bundling it up, making
它是免费的 开源的 把它放在像py pi这样的东西上
it free and open source, and putting it on something like py, pi for others
也可以使用？
to use as well?
好的 我继续运行sayings.py的代码
OK, I'm going to go ahead and run code of sayings.py
创建一个名为sayings.py的全新文件
to create a brand new file called sayings.py which
将会是我自己的语录模块
is going to be my own sayings module.
我将在其中定义几个简单的函数
I'm going to define a couple of simple functions in there.
我将定义一个Hello函数 该函数
I'm going to define a Hello function that's going
要接受名称参数作为输入 请执行以下操作
to take a name parameter as input.
该函数将简单地打印出来
And that function is simply going to print out
一个F字符串 它包含Hello、逗号 然后用大括号括起来
an F string that contains hello, comma, and then in curly braces,
不管那个人到底叫什么名字
whatever that person's name actually is.
然后我将继续定义另一个函数
Then I'm going to go ahead and define one other function,
一个告别功能 有def 再见 也
a goodbye function, that has def, goodbye, also
接受名称作为其输入
takes a name as its input.
然后通过对比打印出来 然后F
And then that prints out by contrast and F
表示再见的字符串 逗号 然后用大括号表示姓名
string that says goodbye, comma, and then in curly braces, name.
现在 只是为了好让我能确定
And now, just for good measure just so I can be sure
这些功能正在按预期运行
that these functions are working as expected,
接下来 我将在这里定义一个主要函数
I'm going to go ahead and define a main function in here
也只是为了测试的目的
too just for the purposes of testing.
接下来 我将定义一个主要函数
And I'm going to go ahead and define a main function that
只是做了几个测试
simply does a couple of tests.
例如 它叫Hello of 引用 引用 不引用 “world” 我们应该说吗？
For instance, it calls Hello of, quote, unquote, "world" shall we say?
然后它也会叫再见 引用 不引用 “世界”
And then it's going to call good bye of, quote, unquote, "world" as well.
希望我在屏幕上看到的是
And hopefully what I'll see on the screen then
当我运行这个程序时 是Hello World和Goodbai World
is Hello world and Goodbye world when I run this program.
当然 像往常一样 我需要明确地告诉
Of course, as always, I need to explicitly tell
来调用该函数
Python to call that function.
所以我将在这个文件的最底部调用Main
So I'm going to call main at the very bottom of this file.
好了 让我们试试看
All right, let's try it out.
Sayings.py的Python 回车
Python of sayings.py, Enter.
事实上 我看到了你好世界和再见世界
And indeed, I see Hello world and Goodbye world.
所以我认为我有理由认为
And so I think it's reasonable for me to assume
这些函数虽然简单 但在这一点上是相当正确的
that these functions, albeit simple, are pretty correct at this point.
但是现在 假设我想要使用这些函数 就好像我确实
But now, suppose that I want to use these functions as though I've indeed
创建了我自己的库 我自己的Python模块 这使得
created my own library, my own Python module and that makes available
Hello函数适用于我或任何其他想要使用
a Hello function for me or anyone else who wants to use
它或再见功能也是如此
it or a Goodbye function as well.
好吧 让我继续 再次敞开心扉 比方说.py 但从头开始
Well, let me go ahead and open up again say.py but start fresh.
与其让牛说什么 不如让我继续说
And rather than have the cow say anything, let me go ahead
让我自己的图书馆来说话
and have my own library do the talking.
所以我要继续 像前面一样 导入sys以便我
So I'm going to go ahead and as before, import sys so that I
可以访问命令行参数
have access to command line arguments.
从我自己的名为Sayings的模块中 我将导入Hello
And from my own module called sayings, I'm going to import Hello.
因此 因为我创建了一个名为sayings.py的文件 所以我可以从Sayings中得出结论
So because I created a file called sayings.py, I can say from sayings.
根据Python的推断 我的意思是Sayings.py
And it's inferred by Python that I mean sayings.py,
至少在这个当前目录中
at least in this current directory.
但我并不打算只导入其中一个函数
But I specifically ain't going to import just one of the functions
就目前而言 就是你好
for now, namely Hello.
现在 我可以做这样的事情了
And now, I can do something like this.
如果用户愿意为我提供两个命令行参数
If the user obliges by giving me two command line arguments, which
我可以通过检查sys.argv的长度进行检查
I can check by just checking the length of sys.argv,
然后 我将继续调用这个新的Hello函数传递
I'm going to then go ahead and call this new Hello function passing
作为它的输入 sys.argvbracket1 它应该是这个人的名字
as its input, sys.argvbracket1, which should hopefully be the person's name
我希望他们能在提示符下输入
which I'm going to expect them to type at the prompt.
所以我们开始吧
So here we go.
我要去我的终端窗口
I'm going to go down to my terminal window,
运行Say.py和我自己的名字的Python 因为我希望我自己的名字以
run Python of say.py and my own name because I want my own name to end up
在命令行参数中 因此成为Hello的一部分
in the command line arguments and therefore, be part of the Hello
因此 当我稍后按回车键时 我应该会看到Hello
so when I hit Enter in just a moment, I should hopefully see Hello,
逗号 大卫
comma, David.
所以我们开始吧 进入
So here we go, Enter.
呵呵 我看到了你好世界 再见世界
And huh, I see Hello world, Goodbye world.
然后我看到了你好 大卫
And then I see Hello, David.
那么 为什么会发生这种情况呢？
So why is this happening?
好吧 事实证明即使我已经做了所有的事情
Well, it turns out even though I've done everything
根据我们自己过去的实践 它并不是真正的
according to our own past practice, it's not really
毕竟 调用Main的方法是正确的
the right way to go about calling main after all.
如果我盲目地调用文件底部的Main
If I'm blindly calling main here at the bottom of my file, that
意味着每当该文件被Python加载时 main都将被调用
means whenever this file is loaded by Python, main is going to get called.
不幸的是 这是真的 即使我正在导入这个文件或者只是
And unfortunately, that's true even if I'm importing this file or just
这个文件中的一个函数 因为我现在在我的say.py程序中
a function from this file as I am here in my say.py program.
这是在这里的第三行 当我从谚语中说
This is to say on line three here, when I say from sayings,
IMPORT Hello 这实际上是在告诉Python
import Hello, this effectively tells Python
要找到那个模块sayings.py 请从上到下、从左到右阅读它
to go find that module, sayings.py, read it from top to bottom, left to right,
然后专门导入Hello函数
and then import specifically the Hello function.
不幸的是 在Python从顶部读取文件时
Unfortunately by the time Python has read the file from top
在底部 从左到右 最后一行代码调用是调用Main
to bottom, left to right, that last line of code recall is to call main.
无论如何 Main都会被调用
Main gets called no matter what.
所以真的 使用main函数的正确方法是
So really, the right way to go about using a main function, which
确实解决了确保我们可以对我们的函数进行排序的问题
does solve that problem of ensuring that we can order our functions
任何我们想要的 所有的功能都将
however we want, and all the functions will
是在调用它们时定义的 即
be defined at the time they're invoked, I
不应该无条件地在这个事件的底部调用Main
shouldn't be unconditionally calling main at the bottom of this
或者实际上是我的任何程序
or really any of my programs.
相反 我应该使用这种技术
I should instead use this technique.
我应该说如果__NAME__==“__Main__” 那么也只有到那时 你才应该真正
I should say if__name__=="__main__", then and only then should you actually
呼叫Main
call main.
好的 原来这个变量是Python中的一个特殊符号__NAME__
Well, it turns out that this variable is a special symbol in Python, __name__.
请注意 由于其字体 VS代码
And notice that VS Code because of its font
并没有显示出这两个下划线
isn't quite showing those two underscores.
但他们确实在那里 在左边和右边
But they're indeed there to the left and the right.
这是一个特殊变量 其值由Python自动设置为
This is a special variable whose value is automatically set by Python to be,
当您从命令行运行文件时 引号 不引号 “main”
quote, unquote, "main" when you run a file from the command line
就像通过运行Sayings.py的Python一样
as by running Python of sayings.py.
所以 现在看看sayings.py中的这个附加条件会发生什么
So watch what happens now with this additional conditional in sayings.py.
如果我运行sayings.py的Python 它仍然像以前一样工作 因为名称将是
If I run Python of sayings.py, it still works as before because name will be
当我使用Sayings.py的Python运行此文件时 自动设置为__Main__
automatically set to __main__ when I run this file using Python of sayings.py.
但请注意这一点
But notice this.
名称不会设置为 引用 不引用 “Main”
Name is not going to be set to, quote, unquote, "main."
它将被设置为其他名称 从技术上讲是模块的名称
It's going to be set to something else, technically the name of the module
当我像这里一样导入文件时
when I instead import the file like I do here.
所以这段突出显示的代码行即使它
So this highlighted line of code even though it
将导致Python查找sayings.py 从上到下阅读它
will cause Python to go find sayings.py, read it from top to bottom,
从左到右 它这次将忽略对Main的调用
left to right, it's going to ignore the call to main this time
因为它包含在条件句中
because it's wrapped in that conditional.
在这种情况下 当我导入文件而不是直接运行它时
In this case, when I'm importing a file and not running it directly
在命令行中 不会调用main
at the command line, main will not get called
根据该Names值的定义
by definition of that names value.
所以 让我继续试一试
So let me go ahead and try this.
而不是运行sayings.py的Python 它
Instead of running Python of sayings.py, which
是包含该条件Main的模块
is the module, which contains that conditional main,
让我在这里继续 运行Say.py的Python
let me go ahead here, run Python of say.py,
这就是我面前的程序 它从Sayings中导入Hello
which is the program here before me that imports Hello from sayings.
但由于这一条件 它不是
But because of that conditional, it's not
在这种情况下 我要向除我以外的任何人打招呼
going to say Hello to anyone else except me in this case.
好了 我们这周末就到了
All right, we're here at the end of our week.
我认为 导入除Hello之外的其他内容才是合适的
It's only appropriate, I think, to import something other than Hello.
为什么我不继续 输入的不是Hello 而是从这里开始的再见
Why don't I go ahead and import not Hello, but Goodbye from here.
让我继续说再见 而不是哈罗
Let me go ahead and call Goodbye instead of Hello.
这一次 当我运行Say.py的Python时
And this time when I run Python of say.py,
我不会打出我自己的名字
I'm not going to type my own name.
请允许我在全世界范围内打字
Allow me if I may to type in the whole world
所以我们今天的最后一句话是再见世界
so that our final sentiment today is Goodbye world.
事实上 本周的情况就是这样
Indeed, that's it for this week.
我们下次再见
We will see you next time.